Heat. Heat.
Good evening and good day everyone and
welcome back to the Ask Abijit show. We
are doing episode
uh 3:40 today and obviously we are
discussing the events that are ongoing
in the Iran conflict, the West Asia
conflict, the Iran conflict and
unfortunately the situation is
escalating. it significantly escalating
and I'll take uh as many of your
questions about this matter as possible
and and other questions as well other
topics if that is what you want uh so we
shall do that but before we start the
proceedings let us see who all is there
on the live chat tonight this fine day
this fine evening Buddha goes nuclear
uh Chit Sharma Chandra Gupta Chandra
Gupta once again Bhavia Bhavya Singh
Chib Anoop Mochi X Gaming Adita Acharia
Ritik Pawar S KR
Rohan Biri says happy guri parva happy
guri parva to all of you thank you very
much
Rajesh Babu is here from Kerala good to
see you sir good to see you pascar
bandit Pyth good to see you as well
geopolitical dub is here from Indor
always good to see you sir singh
um Shishti Siliguri good to see you
Rahul Dunak hello good to see you sir
Sam Bramanik
Putin is also here. Uh
Umar Maheshwari Namaste G. Uh Sherlock
Sherlock Adit Ashwini Sherlock once
again. KYU IPK1s
right angle. Uh Muffet Abishekla live.
Cintillating kids good to see you.
Soldier boy Akit Sharma Ashbini Omar
Nigkar. Hello Omar Nigar. Pranjal Mna
Kotari good evening. Ankit Bazad. Okay.
Shiv Kapoor good evening. The Patak
Arpit good evening. Uh GK GK87. Are you
Singh Pranam Sarji Mlevin good to see
you. Mlevin says who wants to go on a
Dubai trip? Well I'm not sure it's very
advisable right now. Okay. Da Paw Priyud
Om Pranjal Prair Putin good to see you.
Jashir Ram G Vince like swing AG okay
random skull good evening Jri Krishna
Nishan B good evening Himmanurajit
uh DI Shrian Vijay Vagila good morning
good morning to you Donald twink
okay uh Nepu nipuran saran okay
tanesh pandes parush sparush xab
Good evening ma'am. Priyanchu Puli Hola
and so many other people. Shria Smithra
is here from Moscow. Good evening to
you. I suppose it'll be evening soon in
Moscow. Uh Karan Singh Pund, happy
Navaratri. Happy. Yes. Happy Navatri.
Okay. Uh and everyone else. Okay. So
good to see you all. Thank you so much
for being on this live stream. Sam
Winston, Dr. Strange, uh Gree Sahil,
Tanmay Singh, Swastik Kohi, Anurag
Singh, Satyendra,
uh and everybody else. Okay. So let's
get going with some questions. Okay.
What are the questions that we have thus
far? Let's see. Right angle says 5
MWGCMR
for Indian army energy independent your
view. I'm not aware of this weapon. 5
megab JGC
MMR. What is a 5 megawatt GCMR? Let me
try and find out what that is.
Um
okay. Um
five megawatt mega watt G C MR
R what is that?
Um
okay gas cooled micro modular reactor.
Okay. As part of and so on planning for
5 megawatt hour gas cool reactors of
offer advanced flexible decentralized
clean power.
Um what's my view about this? I I would
say it's great.
Yeah. For Indian army. Okay. Okay. So, I
haven't really looked into into the
details and specifications of this uh of
this micro modular reactor, but I think
uh any kind of technological progress
and advancement is good news. So, I
welcome it very much.
Putin says patriots like you and Singh
talked about US influence in northeast.
Okay. I'm not aware of vehab Singh but
if Singh has spoken about this I I
commend that. Thank you Singh for
speaking about this. uh about the US
influence in the Indian Far East, the
northeast and we have been proven to be
100% correct after the recent NIA
arrest.
My respect and trust in you is now
10fold. Well, thank you so much sir. So
what is um Mr. Putin etc talking about?
That's the question right. Um
what do we have? So here uh give me a
second.
Okay let's put this on the screen.
Right. this this piece of news that's
recently uh emerged
uh where is this
this one here? Okay.
So this is from India which is a news
agency Delhi and this is from the 16th
of March. Today is the 19th of March.
This is 3 days ago. So what happened?
What happened is that the National
Investigation Agency of India arrested
seven foreign nationals, six Ukrainians
and one American for allegedly providing
terrorist training in Myanmar. They
received 11-day custody for illegal
entry weapons and drone training and
importing drones from Europe. Now I have
been so when we are talking about
terrorist training in Myanmar. If you
are familiar with the map of India
you will know that Myanmar is right next
to Manipur. And you will also hopefully
know that Manipur is now right now a
disaster zone.
A disaster began in Manipur in May 2023.
Okay.
terrorism, cookie terrorism, large
scale, widespread cookie terrorism,
targeting the indigenous people of
Manipur, the mates and the Nagas.
And now it looks like everything is
fine. The media is not talking about it.
It's not ended. These people have taken
over more than half of Manipur and they
are terrorizing the locals.
And over the past three three or so
years, they have launched all kinds of
horrific attacks on the innocent unarmed
indigenous people. Yeah. Including drone
attacks. Drone attacks.
Yeah. Now, what kind of terrorist
training was this individual with this
individual? So, first of all, who was
arrested? Uh, seven foreign nationals.
Once again, let's go to the screen.
Seven foreign nationals were arrested.
six six Ukrainians and one American.
So these Ukrainians were
part of the well you could say they were
Ukrainian armed forces personnel.
Now the question you could ask yourself
is yourselves is this Ukraine like they
say Slava, Okarini etc. they are
fighting a war for survival against
Russia, right?
and they are roping in civilians to
serve in the armed forces including 50y
old 60 year old men and even pregnant
women have been dragged into the war to
to put on the uniform and fight against
the Russians right so when you have
highquality
Ukrainian armed forces personnel in in
India
why are they in India aren't they
supposed to be fighting for their
homeland but no they are in India
They're crossing over into Myanmar and
training terrorists,
cookie terrorists.
So what does that tell you first of all
about the Ukrainian angle? It tells you
that Zalinski has subordinated his
nation and his people to the interests
and the whims and fancies and
geopolitical games of his masters, the
United States and whoever else it may
be.
Okay. So here we are. So that's what's
happened. Ukraine is no longer an
independent sovereign entity. It never
was. It serves the interests of the
United States. Zalinsky doesn't care
what happens to his people or to his
nation. He's pressing middle-aged men
and pregnant women into the war. But he
has highquality trained mercenaries who
are creating trouble in India, in
Myanmar.
H that's what's happening. That's the
number one. Secondly, there's this
American guy who has been arrested. Now,
who is this fantastic American person
who's been arrested?
It's Matthew Wandik, a private
mercenary.
Okay. This this individual,
he fought in Libya to overthrow through
overthrow the the government of Muhammad
Gaddafi in 2011. We know how that ended
for for Libya. Disaster for Libya. He's
also been involved in other war zones in
Venezuela, in in Iraq,
in whatever else. Okay, so this is the
guy.
Now
see Libyan revolution.
So he was part of that conflict. He
created all the trouble in Libya. I mean
he was he was part of that that entire
thing. Now what else do we have? He is
the founder or co-founder or whatever of
SI International. This Matthew Van Djk
person Matthew Aaron Van Djk Sons of
Liberty International. And this is a
tweet from Sons of Liberty International
from 20 from 2019.
Christian persecution they claim is set
to rise sharply in 2019. Okay. And
obviously they will claim there's
Christian persecution persecution in
India as well. That's what the US
government has been doing for a long
time. And they use this as the pretext
for to create trouble in India.
Okay. And uh yeah
so that is something that happened. What
else do we have? We had a statement by
the government of Ukraine. Let me uh try
and dig that out. Where is this
statement by the government of Ukraine?
Um, give me a second. I will pull that
out and let's put out the statement by
the Ukrainian government. A press
release they have put out. Give me a
second. Okay. Ukrainian press release.
Okay. This one here. This one.
Press release by the embassy of Ukraine
to the Republic of India.
Um, taking into account publicly
available information in the case
concerning the detention of six citizens
of Ukraine, including media reports,
blah blah blah blah blah, the embassy of
Ukraine in India expresses serious
concern regarding the presence of
circumstances that point to a possible
orchestrated and politically motivated
nature of this case and so on. So they
are claiming that our guys are innocent
and you people are doing this for
because of political motivations.
Okay, their guys are terrorists and
mercenaries and they're they're arming
and training cookie terrorists in
Myanmar with the objective of
destabilizing Myanmar as well as India.
And this is the kind of press release
they've put out and this is from a few
hours ago today. Now after this entire
matter happened, the fantastic
ambassador of the US Sergio Gore he
tweeted this yesterday just wrapped up
an extremely fruitful meeting with
national security adviser Ajit Dwal
covered critical security and
geopolitical issues strategic
cooperation between the US and India
continues to advance. So he met with
India's national security adviser Mr.
Dwal Mr. Ajit Dwal
very interesting generally this guy any
an ambassador of the US typically meets
with Indian not typically doesn't
typically doesn't meet the the national
security adviser of India that yeah
something has happened yeah clearly we
know what happened an American terrorist
enabler has been caught in India so I
have been saying this for the longest
time I have been saying this since 2023
when there were no Manipur experts now
everybody is a Manipur expert right
every YouTuber every journalist
everybody Everybody is a Manipur expert.
In 2023 there were no Manipur experts.
At that time I had said this what's
happening in Manipur is not a local law
and order problem. It is not some ethnic
clash between Manipuri tribes. This is a
geopolitical issue
and the objective is to destabilize
India.
The objective all of this is part of
project K cookie land for Christ. I have
been saying this since 2023.
Now you can see and a lot of people said
that you are imagining things this is
just some tribal clash and all that
nonsense where are those people today
everything I've said is now slowly
coming out in the open right
uh so what is the deal in Manipur
and what is the deal with Myanmar across
Manipur across the border of Manipur to
the east shall we pull out the map
because we do that where's the map okay
let me put the map on the screen um In
case some of you are not aware of the
geography, it's possible. So
we're talking about India's far east
also called India's northeast which is a
misnomer but whatever. So here you have
the state of Manipur which is a disaster
zone absolute disaster zone. East of
Manipur we have this large nation called
Burma. Myanmar
and in the north of Myanmar you have
this territory large territory that is
essentially not no longer administered
by the government of Burma. It is the
wild west you could say right there are
there's a civil war going on in Burma
between various armed ethnic groups
Christian insurgent and terrorist groups
fighting against the government of Burma
and also fighting against India. And if
you go to the east of Manipur and
Nagaland and Misoram, you have this big
territory where you have the cookie
people. Cookies.
The cookies aren't Burmese by the way.
The cookies don't speak the Burmese
language. They don't practice Burmese
culture. They don't even respect Burmese
culture. They're fighting against Burma.
They're fighting against India. They are
fighting against Bangladesh also, right?
and they want to create an artificial
Christian nation a sort of Christian
Pakistan to cut off India's access to
the far east to to East Asia to East
Asia and that is completely in line with
American objectives and the Americans
also want to destabilize China if it can
be done so this cookie terrorism and
project K and cook for Christ it is a
meth a method of killing two stones with
two birds with one stone China as well
as India mostly India the Americans now
have this containment policy towards
India to contain India not allow India
to grow and rise create you know create
all kinds of troubles trouble on various
part in various parts of India and
outside of India borders border regions
to to constantly keep India off balance
and maybe balkcanize India maybe break
off the far east of India from from the
union of India yeah these plants have
been around for a very have been around
for a very long time and the past 70 80
years the whole region has been
Christianized apart from some small
parts of Manipur that is also now going
the mates are also now many of them are
converting to Christianity and the
government of India is waiting and
watching and they have some some there
of their own geopolitical games
multimodal project for that we will sell
off Manipur essentially or let Manipur
go to the dogs or the cookies rather
that sort of thing so that's what's
going on in Manipur it's a disaster zone
and no single government is responsible
for this disaster
The root cause of the disaster is that
there's the presence of lacks of
foreigners
on Manipuri territory. Cookies who are
not Indian who have never been Indian.
They are not even Burmese. They have
come from east of Burma. They've come
from China's the Chinese occupied Yunan
region. That's where they are from.
They're not even Burmese. But now they
they're claiming that they're Indians.
They claim they also claim that they're
Jews. By the way, there is that angle
also in this. They eat dogs. They eat
pork. But they claim to be Jews.
Yeah. So since 1949 when Manipur joined
India became part of the union of India,
the government of India has had this
policy of settling cookies in Manipuri
territory
and Nizaram is very much involved in
this whole matter
and because of this this these these
policies the the the current problem
exists and even in the past 10 years it
looks like lacks more cookies have come
into Manipur and the government probably
was snoozing sleeping
So you can't blame any one government
for the disaster but you cannot exempt
the current government from the
responsibility of from partial
responsibility at least of this disaster
and it's an ongoing disaster. Indian
citizens are affected.
Yeah. Lacks of Indian citizens are
affected and looks like so now that this
is this step has been taken the American
terrorists have been arrested, the
Ukrainian terrorists have been arrested.
What? Why has this happened now?
Maybe the government of India has now
decided we will change our tactics,
change our strategy. I don't know. Or
maybe it's just a bargaining tool. The
Americans of Nikil Gupta, so we will
arrest one American guy and we'll swap
one by one for one. Is that the simple
game you're playing? Or has the
government of India now decided to
rescue Manipur?
Time will tell. So that is the
situation. Manipur disaster, ongoing
disaster in Manipur. You have drones
flying over you know towns and villages
and dropping bombs on people. It's
happening right now. You have large
parts of Manipur where you have
terrorists walking the streets with
AK-47s, M15s and God knows what and
there is no Indian government official
anywhere in sight. It's like that it's
no longer part of India. It's like
cookand has actually become a de facto
nation if not a djour nation. That is
how badly the government of India has
dropped the ball in Manipur. They may
have their own geopolitical agenda to
play. Some kind of god knows what little
little agenda they have,
but hopefully things change now. This is
a good sign that the American and
Ukrainian terrorists have been
apprehended. And the the the chief
minister of Misoram last year last year
had stated that more than 2,000
American and UK personnel had passed
into had crossed into Myanmar from
Misoram from Misaram's territory.
Now if you are a foreigner and you want
to enter Misoram or Manipur, you need an
innerline permit.
Even if you are an Indian citizen who is
not from Manipur or Misoram, you need
something called an innerline permit, a
document and definitely foreigners need
that. So how did these foreigners reach
the play this place come with drones
military you know dual use or or
military use drones and cross over into
Myanmar? Is the government of India
sleeping?
You can't blame Nehu anymore for these
things. Anyhow, that's the situation.
I'll keep an eye on it on this. That's
what I do. Yeah, I've been speaking
about this very clearly since the
beginning of the problem, May 23, when
there were no Manipur experts. So, I'm
going to keep an eye on this. Okay, I'll
keep you guys keep you guys and girls,
ladies and gentlemen, informed about
what is actually truthfully happening.
Not the not the BS propaganda and and
and all the chat GPD analysis that you
see from other other so-called experts.
I'll tell you what's actually happening.
Okay.
Adcharia says how was North Korea able
to get nuclear weapons? Did they make
this on their own or did they get it
from Russia and China? China or Russia.
And how was the why was the US not able
to stop them or chose not to stop them
unlike Iran? Yeah. So look Iran. Yeah.
Good comparison. North Korea versus
Iran, right? It's an excellent and very
pertinent comparison. North Korea versus
Iran. Today, the situation is that Iran
doesn't have nukes, so it's being
pounded. It's obviously fighting back
and it's doing a pretty damn good job of
fighting back. But still, if it if Iran
had even 10 nukes, the situation would
be very different today. Maybe nobody
would have tried starting a war against
them, right? But they don't have nukes.
uh their their supreme leader Mr. Kamei
had issued a fatwa against nuclear
weapons. He was a he was a moderate
relatively speaking right and that's why
Iran is in the situation that it is
today. It's taken tremendous damage
maybe trillions of dollars worth of
damage Iran has taken.
Yeah. So it's fighting back. It's really
hitting hard at at its enemies but it's
also in the process taking tremendous
damage. But look at North Korea. It has
nukes. It has the means to deliver the
nukes to the relevant places. And that's
why nobody dares touch them. Right?
That's the difference. Now the question
you're asking is a pertinent relevant
question. How did North Korea acquire
nuclear weapons?
And why did the US not stop them?
So the US probably was keeping an eye on
North Korea but obviously it's very hard
to penetrate North Korea and know what
actually is up there up to right. Um and
it is said that it is Pakistan that
shared nuclear technology with North
Korea. That is the that is the currently
accepted version of events. the
Pakistanis helped North Korea somehow
the the AQ Khan uh gang or coty or
whatever. So the mythology about
Pakistan's nuclear program is that there
was this rogue nuclear physicist whose
name was Abdul Khad Khan. He was working
somewhere in Europe maybe in the
Netherlands or whatever and he somehow
acquired blueprints of either
centrifuges or whatever and he brought
this blueprints back to Pakistan and
that's how Pakistan got a nuclear
program and they were able to acquire a
new you know to to produce a nuclear
weapon. That is BS.
Okay. I am 99.9% certain that the
Pakistani nuclear weapons are American
weapons on loan. Pakistan is the
custodian of those weapons but it has it
doesn't have the the the the permission
to use these weapons without American
approval
and it's the custodian which means most
likely those weapons are in the hands of
Americans who are on Pakistani territory
that's most likely the case but the
mythology if you extend it is that
Pakistan gave North Korea uh nuclear
technology and the knowhow and the means
to make nuclear weapons so what really
truthfully happened I don't know for
sure Maybe the Chinese helped North
Korea. Maybe the Russians helped North
North Korea. Maybe the the North Koreans
with a little bit of inputs from China
and Russia were able to eventually make
their own nuclear weapon. There was some
Russian help you know non military uh
nuclear knowhow something was uh
provided by Russia to North Korea. So
what actually happened? It's kind of
murky. most likely with Chinese and
Russian help, Chinese and SL or Russian
help and with local expertise that North
Koreans were able to produce nuclear
weapons and they tested nuclear weapons
uh I don't know maybe 10 20 years ago
for for the first time when was the
first test I don't remember maybe 15
years ago or so you can look it up
exactly when it was and the initial
maybe one or two of the initial tests
may not have been completely successful
maybe there were some fizzles or
whatever but eventually by testing more
times they were able to make sure the
design worked properly and then they
were able to, you know, develop ICBMs,
intercontinental range ballistic
missiles that can deliver the the the
package wherever they want to the
relevant nations of North Korea's
interest, which obviously means the
United States. Yeah. Continental United
States. So why were the US not able to
stop them? Well, the US were in no
position to start the Korean War all
over again. Okay. The Korean War ended
in a stalemate.
uh it ended without actual an actual
ceasefire or armistice. So technically
the Korean war is still on
and the US was not in a position to even
if the North Koreans were on the brink
of on the verge of of acquiring nuclear
weapons and maybe hypothetically let's
say the Americans knew about it they
were not in a position to invade and
stop the North Koreans because the North
Koreans have Chinese support and Chinese
assistance. The Chinese would never have
allowed this to happen. Right? So that's
essentially what happened. That's how
the North Koreans acquired nuclear
weapons. Exactly how it happened is kind
of murky. I don't believe the mythology
that Pakistan transferred technology to
North Korea. Uh the truth is uh probably
something else. But that's overall how
it went.
Riddik Paw says they took out the second
most important person after Kami Ali
Larijani.
Now most of the wise leadership is gone.
How can Iran feel this leadership
vacuum?
Right? They have uh killed assassinated
Mr. Kame. They have now assassinated Mr.
Larijani who was the second most
important or second most powerful person
in Iran. Right? And they have
assassinated a lot of the top leadership
of um of Iran.
Um so you could say that most of the
wise leadership the older leadership is
gone
and Mr. Kame he kind of welcomed the the
the the death the martyrdom he did not
he chose not to hide he was in his house
when it was destroyed by American or
Israeli strikes right and apparently Mr.
Lari Jani also did the same. He did he
chose not to hide. He was at his
daughter's house or whatever which is a
probably a well-known place right it's
not a secret place and that's where he
was also killed apart along with some
other family members I suppose. So it
looks like the older leadership the
wiser leadership
okay looks like they have chosen to
embrace death martyrdom whatever you
want to call it. Iran is a Shia Islamic
nation. This is the culture of
martyrdom. They embrace martyrdom and
martyrdom gives them more power, more
more energy. It gives them it gives the
people of Iran, those who believe in
Shia Islam, the determination to fight
back even harder and with more with more
vigor, with more determination, I
suppose, right? Uh so you could say that
most of the older, wiser leadership is
gone. How can Iran fill this leadership
vacuum? Well, Iran is a nation of how
many million people? 90 million. Uh let
me say the population of Iran. So
there's no der of people right let me
see
population of Iran
what is it 90 93 92 93 million people
that's a big population
a couple of let's say 50 guys die 50 of
the top leaders die what's going to
happen nothing's going to happen they'll
find more leaders see first of all Iran
the IRGC the Iran the Islamic Republican
guards thing IRGC u they have
you know reconfigured the nation into a
mosaic system. So Iran has 31 provinces.
Each province is now going to have its
own leadership, its own uh command and
control structure, its own uh reserves
and stocks of
ammunition, weapons, ballistic missiles,
drones,
munitions, whatever fuel. and they are
fighting 31 independent wars against
Israel and the US and whoever else,
right? And each province has its own
command and control structure. So even
if you take out the top guy, the second
guy, the third guy, whatever, they're
going to have this this whole command
and control structure and more people
will be promoted. One of the things that
happens, you know, warfare obviously is
a horrible thing,
but typically when a nation is at war
and let's say in in in on the
battlefield you have you have let's say
a regiment or whatever a brigade, a
platoon, a brigade or regiment and the
commander is killed. What happens? Do
they stop fighting? Not at all. That's
instantaneous field promotion of the
senior most next senior most guy.
instantaneous field promotion and
generally that gives you better
leadership because the non-field
promotions are typically bureaucratic in
nature but when there's a battle going
on and your top guy is dead you're going
to promote the most capable person so
that you all survive
it maybe it's done by rank or maybe it's
done by by capability. So typically when
you have multiple field promotions two
three guys die and you keep promoting
that's when the most capable leadership
emerges someone who can you know win
your battle for you or or die in the
process.
So when you have a nation of 90 billion
million people
assassinating the top 50 people the top
100 people if you have the right
structure is not going to make any
difference whatsoever.
Typically in a stagnant society, a
sedentary society, a society that hasn't
seen war in decades. In that sort of
society, you have something called the
overproduction of elites.
And these elites who are overproduced by
these stagnant sedentary societies. They
take up all the positions of power and
they over time the system becomes a rent
rent seeking system.
When you have this sort of situation
where the elites are being taken out by
the enemy and you have field promotions
essentially, that's when the problem of
over production of elites is taken care
of. It's sorted out and you have the
best most capable leadership rising to
the top. So this is actually a good
problem for Iran to have. And it's it's
a bad thing. It's a terrible thing for
the US and for Israel because the
moderates, they've killed them all.
They've killed off all the moderates.
Ali Kame the Ayatah, the supreme leader,
he was against nuclear weapons. He was
in favor of negotiations and some
settlements. That's why you had the
JCPOA and the joint comprehensive plan
of action, the Iran nuclear deal that
Trump eventually walked out of
unilaterally.
Ali Kame is what is who is the person
who made this possible.
Right? So those who are in favor of
negotiations, those who are in favor of
moderation, those who are against
nuclear weapons, they have been killed
by the Americans and the Israelis. So
who rises to the top now? is the
hardliners, those who don't want
negotiations anymore. No more
negotiations.
And the US apparently has tried on at
least three occasions to open back
channels with Iran since the war began
and try to find some way of negotiating
with Iranians and and you know going for
a ceasefire, a face saving ceasefire.
And the Iranians are saying go to hell.
No negotiations, no talks. The war goes
on and if Iran is is in a position to re
to to to
rebuff American overtures for a
ceasefire, it tells you the Iranians
believe they're going to they're going
to prevail.
So yeah, that is what it is.
Basar Bandit says Pyth to you as well.
All well yes here. Yes sir. Are we
reaching closer to a time about Shir
Shinszu AB's statement of Japan having
nuclear capabilities considering the
current events are a measure to contain
China? China. China
I think we are coming closer. See it was
not Mr. Shinszo Abbe who said this. It
was Shri Kissinger. Henry Kissinger a
few months maybe 3 months before he
tragically passed away. Shri Kissinger
had said that Japan is um it it could
become a nuclear weapons power within
within the next five years and he said
that in 2023.
So we still have a couple of years to go
right and it's I think it's highly
likely that within by 28 or so Japan
could become a nuclear weapons power.
Now in what circumstances does it become
a new see we know that the current war
was about you know about containing
China the the West Asia the Iran war the
Americans and is the Israelis wanted to
do a regime change and install a puppet
but the Americans wanted to acquire
complete control of Iran's energy
resources so that those that can be
denied to China. The same was the case
with Venezuela to acquire to to to steal
the energy or to control the energy.
Right? So one of the angles in this war
is China to control China contain China
that obviously has not worked out very
very well at all. It's been a disaster.
And now that the Americans are in a
situation where they are where where
they are depleting very rapidly their
resources, their reserves of whether it
is cruise missiles, whether it is
munitions or whatever interceptors,
missile interceptors, all that stuff.
They're going to have to fall back on
the cap, industrial capabilities of
other nations like European nations,
also Japan, South Korea, etc. And since
the Americans are on the back foot and
they're running short of very critical
munitions and uh weapons, the Chinese
will now feel emboldened and they'll
feel that you know what we have we now
can see how the Americans can be
defeated and we can use those lessons in
Taiwan and let's go for Taiwan that sort
of thing. So the Americans will be very
very cognizant of this possibility
and that's why they could very well give
the green signal to Japan to nuclearize.
Now, what kind of nuclearization could
it be? That's a question. Will the
Americans have Japan
develop and test and then deploy its own
nuclear weapons? Japan is very capable
of doing that. Or will the Americans use
the Pakistani approach
of making the nation of Japan the
custodian of American weapons under
American control? Most likely the
latter.
But yes, this could very well happen
sooner rather than later.
Basar bandit again. Hindu
to everybody. Hindu
wish you a very happy Hindu. No.
Observation. A number of viewers on live
stream has increased in follower account
to post 2024 election for the first
time. Requesting everyone watching to
like and check your subscriptions. Thank
you very much. Very kind of you sir.
Yes, everyone please like like and
subscribe. Check that you subscribed. my
subscribers are being auto have the past
couple of years have been automatically
unsubscribed in large numbers uh by
whatever process I don't know uh but now
it looks like things are kind of on a
better yeah somewhat better for the
channel so please check if you're
subscribed or not lots of people I'm
told are not getting notifications a lot
of people I I hear are not able to
comment at all so there's all kinds of
problems but it is what it is so anyway
Please check that you're subscribed and
please do like the the the the video. I
never ask anyone to like, subscribe, all
that. Please do that. Thank you. Thank
you.
Basar bandit says as usual temporary
nation Pakistan did horrible ghastly
things in Afghanistan. 200 to 400 lives
lost in air strikes. Is this a step to
avoid fighting with Iran? what what
possible retaliation of guns are likely
to do apart other than the Taliban,
Pakistan, Baljasthan, Liberation Army
etc. So let's uh quickly
give me a second. Yeah. So the the
Pakistanis these cowardly Pakistanis
they launched an air strike on Kabul. It
the the the bombs struck
a hospital which was a drug
rehabilitation center. Okay. where
people who were uh
uh hooked on drugs, what's it called?
Addicted to drugs, they were being
rehabilitated and apparently between 2
to 400
patients
were killed in this Pakistani air
strike. These are innocent civilians.
Right now
before I I even discuss that, I want to
show you something really
really I would say really interesting.
Give me a second. Yeah. So this is a
tweet. I I want to show you a tweet by
someone.
Okay. Uh
give me a second. Yeah. Okay. Here we
go.
This is a tweet by an account called
Mossad commentary. It's got a million
subscribers. It is based in Israel. I am
I am not claiming this is the account of
Mossad itself. It's a Mossad commentary
account. It's based in Israel. It's
unofficial
which means that it could or could maybe
it is official, maybe it's not, but
they're claiming that it's an unofficial
account. But it is very much an Israeli
account. So here's what this Israeli
account says. The Kabul site is not a
drug rehab center.
Again, but to be clear, this was a
Taliban weapons and ammunition storage
site, not a drug drug rehabilitation
center. How does Mossad know this?
How does Mossad know or this Israeli
account know that the uh that the
hospital that was destroyed by the
Pakistanis was not a drug rehab center.
It was an Taliban weapons and ammunition
storage site. How does this is Israeli
account know that Pakistan's arms forces
launched operation Gazaboo whatever
overnight on March 16 carrying out
precision air strikes against Afghan
Taliban regime facilities ti t t t t t t
t t t t t t t t t t t t t t tied to
terrorism. Israel is claiming that that
this Israeli account is claiming that
Taliban are terrorists and Pakistan are
are are not terrorists. They are
fighting terrorism.
Targets included two sites in Kabul and
four in Nangar where ammunition deposed
etc etc used to support terror proxies
were reportedly destroyed according to
Pakistan's information minister. So
these guys are paring Pakistani
propaganda
this Israeli account. Now Israel is a
nation that Pakistan does not recognize
as a nation.
So why is an Israeli account that claims
to be unofficial Mossad
paring Pakistani propaganda portraying
the Taliban as terrorists? The
Pakistanis as those who fight terrorism
when we know and the whole world knows
that Pakistan is the global epicenter of
terrorism and this air strike on a
hospital is another example of Pakistani
terrorism and this Israeli account
is trying to whitewash this Pakistani
crime. What's going on?
Full support, sir. Yes, India. Full
support. Full support. Keep it up. Full
support.
When will you people wake up that there
are no allies that India has? There are
no friends that India has.
I'm not saying Israel is an enemy. I'm
saying that Israel is a nation with its
own interests.
As as it should be. My point is why do
you give full support to other nations?
You should give issue based support to
every single nation apart from your own.
Full support should be only to your own
nation.
We have a tremendous
amount of shared interests with Israel.
On those issues, we will give support to
Israel.
But they don't give unconditional
support to anybody. Here the Israelis
are supporting Pakistan.
who is our ally so to say it's
Afghanistan not Pakistan
and we know we have suffered at the
hands of Pakistan for decades Pakistani
terrorism
funded and financed by whom the United
States who gives unconditional support
to Israel and see who this Israeli
account is supporting Pakistan
Pakistan
now the question is u is this a step to
this this Pakistani terrorist strike on
400 people killing them. Is it a step to
avoid fighting with Iran?
Um
what is Pakistan trying to they're
concerned about Afghanistan. They're
concerned about the Taliban. The Taliban
are pun nationalists. The Pakist the
Taliban claim a large piece of territory
that is currently occupied by Pakistan
which is Karakunwa which is historically
pashon territory. So it needs it should
be logically by be part of Afghanistan
and that's the big territorial dispute
that you have and the Pakistani military
is concerned about that and maybe if the
Pakistanis get involved in you know
along in in the next few days or weeks
in the Iran war then if there's an
ongoing war with Afghanistan also which
is escalating then they can blame things
on that and also there could be the BRA
mangle Pakistan is a US puppet a US
wasal
and the Americans want Bagram. So maybe
the Pakistanis are trying to soften up
the Afghanistan government in order to
hand over Bagram if possible to the
Americans. That's also a possibility.
Okay. So now what possible retaliation
the Afghans are likely to do apart from
Talib Pakistan, Balojasthan, Liberation
Army, etc.
The Afghans will retaliate through all
kinds of different means including
asymmetric means including
non-conventional unconventional
asymmetric warfare tactics
all kinds of things like that. Uh this
matter is not going to die down. The
Afghans will extract a complete revenge
on Pakistan. Maybe if not in one strike
over a period of maybe it will be spread
out over hundreds of strikes over
Pakistan. But the Afghans will extract
revenge for this and hopefully this is
the beginning of the end for Pakistan in
some shape or form or the other.
Okay. Putin says congratulations on 953
K subs not noticeable increase. Thank
you very much sir indeed. Uh yeah things
seem to be going in the right direction
very slowly very gradually but one
welcomes that. So thank you very much
and it's all thanks to you all. Thank
you.
KYU says, "I work in a non- techch MNC
role. I want to boost my income by
learning finance skills. Can you please
suggest genuine courses for future
upcoming job roles? I seek guidance.
Uh do you want to boost your income by
learning finance skills?"
Finance skills and you
seek guidance. You want genuine courses
for future upcoming job roles. Um,
finance skills. I I am not a finance
guy.
Um, yeah, I I am sorry, but I am not the
right person to ask this question.
Oh, I'm not a finance guy. I don't know
what courses are available, what courses
exist or not. I suppose you could go to
websites like Udemy or whatever. UDB
probably is is a good uh place. It is
also Corsera
and you can search for various finance
skill related uh courses on those
platforms. That's where you would find
any and I'm sure you will be able to see
how many people are enrolled on each
course and what is the star rating out
of five or 10 or whatever on for each of
the courses. So if you have a course
where you have let's say 10,000 people
enrolled and it's uh uh it's let's say
above four star rating out of five ID
above 4.5 rating then you can be pretty
sure it's a good course. So that's how I
would suggest you do that's what I would
suggest you do. I am not an expert on
learning finance skills and I am
definitely not aware of any courses
for finance skills. So I'm sorry I can't
help you directly but please go and do
uh try what I'm saying. go to Corsera or
or or Udemy and I'm sure there are high
quality courses available there. All
right, sir. All the best.
Sait
Javad laa
has become new member. Well, thank you
very much and welcome to the channel's
membership. Thank you.
Right angle says if we use microp
pyrolysis technology we have 3 years
diesel.
Um okay, what is microp pyrolysis?
LissIS means breaking of something.
Um,
hemolysis is nasty. That's the it's a
bad kind of lysis.
Hydrarolysis is is is the dissociation
of water into hydrogen and oxygen. So,
what is micropyrolysis?
Pyro means heat.
Pyro pyrochnics. Pyro means heat. Okay.
What is micro py pyrolysis?
Micro pyro microwave. No, it's micro
pyrolysis.
Micropyrolysis. Come on. Here we have
it. What is this?
Uh, efficient thermal degradation
process that uses microwave energy to
heat materials, etc., etc. Okay, talking
about diesel. Diesel
micro pyrolysis diesel
decompose waste plastics, tires, etc.
into high value liquid fuels like
diesel, gasoline and kerosene.
Um, okay. Interesting. Okay. I'll not
look into the details but yeah
interesting. So I looks like it's a
interesting and uh useful technology. I
hope the government looks into it. Yeah.
If somebody from the government is
watching please uh take note of this.
looks like it's a promising technology
that can potentially solve at least some
part of India's u you know requirements
for energy
says thoughts on the recent van dyke
arrest by the national investigative
energy um agency I spoke about this in
detail u it's a good thing
uh that it gives me hope that maybe the
government is now serious about uh you
know redressing addressing and
redressing the sit the situation in
Manipur. Yeah. Well, let's see.
Hopefully, and it's obviously going to
be a message to the Americans
and maybe it is an outcome of the
ongoing turn of events in West Asia
possibly. See, the situation for the US
is bad in West Asia. It wants to leave
this war, but it can't without losing
face.
So American prestige has has taken a big
hit.
America the kind amount of leverage the
US has over other nations
is less now. So maybe it's a good time
for the for India to maybe
address the situation manipur and send a
message to the Americans. Yeah. So maybe
that's what it is. Wy BKT has gifted one
membership of the channel. Thank you
very much. It's very kind of you sir
ma'am. Thank you.
MK says, "MU N's a good place for people
interested in geopolitics." What's a
mun?
Mu n's a good place for people
interested in geopolitics. I don't know
what an MU is. If you could give me the
full form, what is that? Let's see.
M geopolitics.
What's MUN? Model United Nations. It's a
waste of time.
absolute waste of time. That's how I see
it. Uh but yeah, you don't have to rely
on what I say. Please do your own
research and due diligence. From my
perspective, it's a waste of time.
Jagadah Mahavira says, "Show us the
doomsday agreement.
The has USA ability to nuke every
country if all allies and non-allies
corner us if they are cornered?" There's
no doomsday agreement or document or
whatever. But that's what the US will
do.
Okay? They don't publish these
documents.
Those who know know about this. These
documents aren't published. They don't
put out a PDF on a US government
website. There's no agreement with other
nations. This is a policy or a strategy
or you could say a fallback option. Last
what's it called? Deadman's switch kind
of thing.
There's no agreement that's available.
There's no PDF available. There's
nothing available. Nobody publishes this
sort of stuff. But that's what will be
done.
Yeah. Okay.
Deep learner says only war in town now.
Re I have no idea what it means but
okay.
Okay. Anoj says what do you think? Who
can be more threat to India's national
security and sovereignty between China
and the US in the future?
To be very honest and straightforward,
both are big threats. The Americans seek
to create all kinds of problems for
India. They seek to contain India. They
have effected three regime changes in
India's immediate neighborhood, East and
West Pakistan and Nepal.
They are currently
fueling the flames
of the the the the U civil war in
Myanmar which has by design spilled over
into India and made a mess of Manipur
created the Manipur disaster.
The Americans play all kinds of
subnational diplomacy games and engage
with various anti-government political
parties in India. They do all kinds of
things such as this
and they
fund the industrial scale
demographic re-engineering efforts that
are going on in India. Christian
conversions and other conversions also
they're pouring billions of dollars
every year, maybe tens, maybe hundreds
of billions of dollars every year into
India for these activities.
The Chinese don't do any of this.
See the let's say America wins they'll
break up India into 50 pieces and also
destroy India's culture and
civilization. If the Chinese win they
will simply break India into multiple
pieces but they will they don't care
about Indian culture or civilization.
They don't care about that. They'll be
satisfied with breaking India into
multiple pieces. The Americans won't be
satisfied with that. They will also
after the break India into into pieces
they will seek they seek to further
annihilate India's culture and
civilization. So who's more of a threat?
I think you you need to decide on your
own who is more of a threat. But
obviously China is right next door and
we have a big u enormous undemarcated
border with China.
So China from that geographical
proximity perspective is more of an
immediate threat from that perspective.
But it's not like there's no
geographical proximity with between
India and American vasals east, west,
Pakistan, Nepal and so on so forth. And
India is super compromised and
penetrated deep inside within India
itself by the Americans. So
who's more of an immediate threat?
Make your own decisions.
Ary, thank you very much. Aryat
Nlesh Ranjan Shivas says is LNG
including LPG, CNG not available from
Russia? The Russians also produce LNG
LPG whatever. What was what was
Nordstream 2? What was Nordstream 2?
Let's Let's see.
Nordstream 2.
What was that? It was a natural gas
pipeline from Russia to Germany running
through the Baltic Sea. So natural gas
is LNG, which is LPG, CNG, whatever you
want to call it. Same thing. So the
Russians can certainly they certainly do
produce this in very large quantities
and I suppose they could bottle it up
and send it in large quantities to India
as well. So that's an option certainly
but it's a far away option. So if you
put let's say if you if you put LG uh
cylinders let's say onto a ship
and you make it sail from Russia to
India it'll take 25 to 30 days for the
ship to eventually reach India. If you
are importing LNG from Qatar it'll take
like what 5 days for it to reach India.
So it's immediate you get it immediately
like almost immediately.
I don't think it will take five days,
maybe three days or whatever it is,
right? So you you'll get it immediately
or or almost immediately when it comes
from Russia, it takes a long time. But
it's certainly a fallback option for
India for sure. Yeah. So I'm sure it
will have to be activated now because
there's a disaster ongoing ongoing
disaster in in in in the Gulf. What kind
of disaster? Uh the Paris airfield has
been blown up and so on. Let's take a
look at this. Let's take a look at
what's happened.
uh here and Trump has tweeted or or
posted about this statement from uh
President Trump on the South Paris gas
field. Israel out of anger for what's
taken place in the Middle East. Yes, of
course, naturally out of anger has
violently lashed out at a major facility
known as the South Paris gas field in
Iran. A relatively small section of the
hole has been hit. The US knew nothing
about this particular attack. Obviously,
the Israelis don't tell the Americans
anything. And the country of Qatar was
in no way, shape, or form involved with
it, nor did it have any idea that it was
going to happen. Unfortunately, Iran did
not know this or any of the pertinent
facts pertaining to the South Paris
attack and unjustifiably and unfairly
attacked a portion of Qatar's LNG gas
facility. No more attacks will be made
by Israel pertaining to this extremely
important and valuable South Paris gas
field unless Iran unwisely decides to
attack the a very innocent in this case
Qatar in which instance the US with or
without the help or consent of Israel
will massively blow up the entirety of
the south Paris gas field at an amount
of strength and power blah blah blah. I
don't want to authorize this level of
violence and destruction because of the
long-term implications it will have on
the future of Iran. But if Qatar's RNG
is again attacked, I will not hesitate
to do so.
That's what Trump has said. Okay. And as
you can see here, there's a disaster
going on. This is
uh Russ Lafan in Qatar. So the Israelis
first hit at struck at the Iranian par
South Paris gas field and in response to
that the Iranians struck Ras Lafan in
Qatar. It's a huge huge complex and Russ
Lafan and South Paris are the same gas
field. See look here.
So South Paris is in black and the
Russan
the the Qatar Northfield is in orange.
They are part of the same gas field but
the black part is uh is within Iran's
territorial uh waters and the orange
part is within Qatar's territorial
waters or or exclusive economic zone
actually exclusive e economic zone not
territorial waters. So if you blow up
one it obviously will destroy the other.
If Trump says I'll blow up South Paris
it's also going to completely destroy
the North Qatar gas field.
So the the question is why did Israel do
this? The Israelis are hellbent on
escalating
if the Americans allegedly are trying to
deescalate and and find an off-ramp. The
Israelis are trying to make sure this
never happens.
And you can see some frustration from
Trump as well. And Trump knows that if
he if he destroys South Paris, it will
also destroy Qatar's gas field because
it's the same gas field divided into two
by an imaginary line. Right?
That is what is going on. An ongoing
disaster. This war is escalating. It's
escalating.
This is the opposite of deescalation and
hopefully an end to the war. It's going
from bad to worse. Who gave the Israelis
the brilliant idea of destroying or or
trying to trying to damage a very one of
the world's most important gas fields.
And
this is going to have an big impact on
India.
In India, people cook using gas, natural
gas, LNG. In India, it's called CNG or
LPG or whatever. Lots of vehicles run on
on on these gas cylinders, right? And
India doesn't have strategic reserves of
this LG, LPG, CNG. We have strategic
reserves of oil, petroleum, but not of
LNG. So if the supplies through the Gulf
of Formos stop,
India won't have cooking gas and that's
going to be felt immediately
and there that's why India, the
government of India will have to find
alternative sources from which to
procure
LNG.
One possibility is Russia. Uh I'm sure
the government of India is exploring
very urgently all the possibilities.
Yeah. So Russia is definitely a
possibility. Do they see the Russians
generally sell oil through pipelines?
Nordstream 2 is an example. Do they have
the ability to bottle the oil? I mean
the gas to liquify it and bottle it and
ship it. I suppose that's not a
high-tech thing. I'm I'm sure it can be
even if they don't have the the
facilities, they can set it set it up
quickly. I'm sure.
But yeah, one thing is for sure.
Wherever India gets its LNG from, the
prices are going to be higher now
because it's going to be available at a
premium.
So the Americans and Israelis have
created a global disaster, an absolute
global disaster.
The world is never going to be the same
again.
This is a permanent change that we are
seeing in the world. Now they've created
created a global disaster for the entire
world's economy.
This is going to cost India a lot of
money. Lot of money. Billions of
dollars. Tens maybe hundreds of billions
of dollars. Will the Americans and
Israelis pay reparations to India?
Did India do anything to harm these two
countries? No.
We are being harmed by these people's
actions.
And not just India. Everyone's being
harmed by them.
The Japanese, the Chinese, the
Indonesians, our neighbors, all of them.
Absolute disaster.
Okay, team talk says, "I just watched
all of Professor Jang's videos on game
theory, and I must say his views and
your views are pretty similar. It's like
you in Chinese body." Really? Really?
Okay.
Interesting.
Is it I mean, are our views that
similar?
Well, that's that's really interesting.
Okay. Thank you for letting me know.
Thank you.
Vishal R says, "Isn't this the ideal
time for Russia to exhaust the air
defenses of Ukraine and build more
pressure on the US to support two wars?
And can the US seize Kara Island by
putting boots on the island there? I
think it's a good time for Russia to
to to achieve its military and political
objectives in Ukraine.
If Russia makes big advances now as they
are certainly capable of
then it's going to put immense pressure
on the US to it's going to have to you
know like you say a support to wars so
the question is when is the rasputita
season that is the big question let's
let's find out what is rasputita I I'll
tell you it's it's the it's the mud
season in Ukraine and Russia
rasputita season.
So it's spring and autumn. Okay. In
spring you have throwing snow. Autumn
you have heavy rains, mud season. It's
it's twice a year. So this happens in
October, November and also April May. So
April, May you can't really make big
advances. You can't really launch big
campaigns, military campaigns because
your tanks, your your vehicles etc. are
going to get bogged down in the muddy
terrain.
April, May, we're in March right now.
So, if Russia wants to do something,
it's got about 10 days to go, maybe a
week or 10 days.
Doesn't look like they're they're about
to try something.
Uh yeah, so maybe now is not a very good
time to to to to to make a big
offensive, but they can certainly
exhaust air defenses and so on. Putin
has decided to weaponize time. He wants
this war to drag on drag drag on as long
as needed so that Europe is is is
uh Europe's supplies are exhausted.
Supplies of munitions, supplies of
patients, supplies of whatever else are
exhausted, depleted. That's what Putin
is doing. is weaponizing time and
doesn't look like he is in in any hurry
to do something right now despite the
ongoing war uh that Iran is u is facing
right now. The next question is can the
US seize the Ka island by putting boots
on the island there? Well, first of all,
let's see where is this Kar island. It's
a very important island for Iran. Okay,
so let's see if the geography gives us
any clues.
Here's the map. Where is Ka Island? So
we don't talk we are not talking about
Kashma island which is here. This is
Kashma. We're talking about Kha Island.
Where is Kara Island? This is Ka Island.
Now it's as you can see it's very close
to the coastline of Iran. Shall we see
how far it is? What's the distance? The
distance over here it's about 30 35 km
from the coastline. So you can't see it
if you're standing on the Iranian coast,
but it's just like 30 35 kilometers
away.
Now we need to take a look at the
topography
of Iran to get a better understanding.
Give me a second. Do I have that map?
Relief map of Iran? Give me a second.
I'll put that up.
Okay. So now that we have we understand
where Ka Island is, the question is, is
it defensible? Can the Iranians defend
it? So, here's a relief map, exaggerated
relief map of Iran. Okay.
And if you see this, you will see that
Kar Island is located to it's not being
I don't think it's shown here, but it's
close to a very mountainous part of
Iran. Okay? It's close to a to a very
mountainous part of Iran that Iran can
most likely defend.
So if Iran has uh anti- anti- ship
missiles, anti-aircraft missiles etc. uh
you know hidden away in the mountains,
it'll be almost impossible for the
Americans to uh to target those all of
them successfully. So I think it will be
the Americans may be able to take the
island. Will they be able to keep the
island is a is a big question. I think
it will be very difficult for them to
keep the island to defend the island,
hold on to it.
So I think even that is a pretty
suicidal position uh proposition. Yeah.
So Tendra says Israel attacked South
Paris. How will Iran retaliate? How
should other or all Gulf countries
defend themselves after this? Any
reaction from Russia expected? So I
think I kind of discussed this but we
can discuss it all over again if you
like. I mean not all over again but
yeah. So clearly this has happened.
Donald Trump put out his uh big
statement etc. And how did Iran
retaliate? Iran retaliated like like I
put it on the screen. Let's say well
let's do it again.
Um here we have it. Iran retaliated by
targeting the Ras Lafan
um area of of Qatar, right? The Ras
Lafan complex. And this is the situation
also ras aluja.
So Iran can hit uh can can target the
various installations that you have in
Qatar, in Saudi Arabia, in Kuwait,
very big targets, pretty pretty much
sitting ducks. And now the American most
of the American interceptor missiles
have been exhausted.
Most of the TH systems are offline.
There are only two I think both were
both the radars were taken out. So it's
almost impossible for the Americans to
defend Qatar, Kuwait, whoever Saudi
Arabia.
So if Israel, so Israel, what it is
doing is trying to provoke Iran into
hitting more Gulf nations so that the
war escalates and the Americans can't
extricate them out themselves out of
this situation. Israel is trying to
escalate the war.
Brilliant. You're doing a great service
to the to the entire world, Israel.
Great job. Right. So Iran will retaliate
if Iranian facilities are hit, oil
facilities or whatever. Iran has lots of
targets to choose from.
No one's going to stop them. No one's
going to be able to stop them. Uh how
should other Gulf nations defend
themselves after this?
All they can do is ask the Americans,
request the Americans to to safeguard
them, to protect them. But the Americans
look like it doesn't look like they're
in a position to help them. The thing is
if the Gulf nations launch start start
launching strikes at Iran,
then they become legitimate targets.
Right now, Iran is saying that we are
only responding to uh provocations.
We are not targeting the civilians and
infrastructure and so on of the Gulf
nations. We are only doing a tit fortat
response. So in the Gulf nations,
whatever missiles or drones the Iranians
have launched, they have been until now
launched at American military
installations or what Iranians or or
what the Iranians consider to be
legitimate targets as a tit fortat uh
response.
But if the Gulf nations start hitting
out at Iran and targeting military
facilities or something, then Iran will
retaliate much harder against those
countries and target their
infrastructure much more, which will be
a disaster for the Gulf countries. So
that's why Saudi Arabia, Kuwait, Kuwait,
anyway, it's not a big power. Saudi
Arabia also is taking out of this
because the Iranians launched a strike
on a Saudi airfield and destroyed five
American
gigantic refueling planes, but those
were American assets, not Saudi assets.
The Saudis are kind of staying out of
it. They also have a military, but
they're staying out of it. And the same
goes for the UAE and so on. So I think
these nations should it would be in
their best interest to stay out of this
as long as possible and not start
responding.
Gorovnis Sunnis says happy guri padwa
and new year to you and all others in
the chat. Thank you very much Gorov. I
wish you and all the all the viewers a
happy guripadwa and a happy new year.
Right. Angle says government says it
will take 10 years to fence the
Indommyanmar border. Till then if we
deport cookies they will come back.
Consequence for India if we touch cookie
now.
Well this is a problem for the
government of India to solve. Look
solutions they have to find. I can
propose solutions. Others can propose
solutions. Citizens can propose propose
solutions. But it is the government
which is elected by the people whose job
it is to solve the problem.
If they were able to allow a few lakh
cookies to come into India over the past
10 years allegedly, then I'm sure they
can find ways and means of deporting
them from India
and it doesn't have to we don't have to
wait until for 10 years until the whole
border is fenced. I am sure we have
something called the Assam rifles
in Manipur.
What is the job of the Assam rifles?
It's a paramilitary force. It's not it's
not the Indian army or the Indian
military. It's a police force who wear
army uniforms. It's a paramilitary
force. What is the job of the Assam
rifles? Is it not to safeguard India's
territorial sovereignty and integrity
and to make sure that foreigners don't
enter Indian territory? What's the job
of the BSF?
Don't we have sufficient forces deployed
in Manipur?
Can't we
leverage the presence of these forces to
ensure that all illegals are deported?
Why do we need to have fencing of
borders?
I mean, it's necessary, sure. But even
while the border is slowly being fenced,
our paramilitary forces can do their job
for a change, right?
And these are foreigners. These are
illegals.
they have to be thrown out.
So the this is a problem of the
government's own making. These people
come into India in large numbers.
They're allowed to settle down. They're
allowed to set up new villages.
Map data over the past 10 years shows
you an explosion of thousands of new
villages over the past few years.
So we know which villages are new. And
we know that the cookies aren't Indians.
Deport them all. Even if they have
acquired somehow Indian documentation,
deport them all. The government has to
find a solution.
And they can't say that this it's too
complicated or whatever. Find a
solution. Get rid of the foreigners.
Deport the illegals. Deport the cookies.
Deepport the Rohhingas. Deport the
Bangladeshes. Deport the Pakistanis.
What are you waiting for?
Are these people necessary
in India? Is it necessary for for us to
have this to to keep supporting these
people and their descendants in India?
Is that why we pay taxes?
You dug
us into this mess? You dig us out of it?
Yeah.
Anoj art says India is India really
competent or just great marketing? Well,
I'm not sure what is the specific
question. Competent in what? Competent
in uh sky sky skydiving. competent in uh
in in in in mountaineering, competent in
missile engineering, competent in
satellite engineering, competent in uh
scuba diving, competent in what
it it helps if you are a little more
specific, you see.
Yeah. Are the people competent? Is the
government competed? Is some corporation
competent?
Is the military competent? Is the
cricket team competed? Is the hockey
team competent? What is the question?
India is so big, so vast that I can't
make general statements. Please be a
little more specific. It will help me
and that way you'll you'll also get an
answer.
Buddha goes nuclear.
Why can't we move people from the
central region to boundary regions and
change demography in our favors? Soviet
Union used to do it successfully because
India is a democracy. In India, we do it
to hurt ourselves. In India, we change
the demography not in our favor but
against our favor. We allow foreign
mission rays to pump in billions of
dollars to change the religion of
Indians on an industrial scale. We allow
tens of millions of Bangladeshes to come
and squat in India to change the
demography of our cities, towns and
villages. We allow god knows how many
Rohingyas to come into India to change
our demography. We allow lacks of
cookies to squat in our territory
and acquire Indian documentation and
become government servants and what not.
When operation sundur happened, we
suddenly discovered tens of thousands of
Pakistanis who have been living in India
for decades.
We are doing the opposite of what you
are suggesting
of what you are recommending. What you
are recommending is what India should be
doing. But why can't we do it? You have
to ask the government of India who have
been in power for 11 12 years now. You
have to ask them. I don't have any
answer. I am lost for an answer.
I I don't have an answer. Really, we
should do these things. We do the
opposite.
Right. Angle says, "Should India go for
1,000 pages instead of 114 Rafals at $40
billion? Why India going with US engine
for MK2 project? Did the US send us
faulty engines? Your views? Thanks."
Okay. The US has I don't know if the
engines they've sent to India are faulty
that they've sold to India are faulty
but India India has uh paid them a big
amount of money for a number of engines
and they're not delivering those those
engines they are delivering like two or
three engines a year or something
let's say you they're supposed to
deliver x number of engines per year
they're not even delivering x2 or x3
they're delivering a small small number
of engines per year so that they're
essentially choking and killing the the
program Right. Why is India going with
the US engine for Mark 2 project? Well,
because we don't have an engine of our
own and maybe the Russian Saturn engine
is too large.
Maybe other engines are I don't know.
There are all kinds of engines available
but none of them is a sovereign engine
for us. Right. Uh we are now going for a
combined joint project with the French
uh company Snakema. No, Safar.
And in a few years we're going to have
an indigenous engine which is
co-developed with Safar. But that's a
few years down the line. In the
meanwhile, I hear that there is some
good progress with the cavary engine. U
we have developed our own single crystal
blade uh turbine turbine blade
technology.
Uh single a single crystal made of a
certain alloy of metals and that solves
the problem for us. And we also have
successfully tested the afterburner
technology for the cover engine. So two
big problems solved. The only question
is what is going to be the the
how long how many hours can an engine be
run before it has to be serviced or or
hold that's the only question even if
it's 50 hours I think it's a good enough
engine I would say and what's the size I
think the size also it's not too large
or the weight also isn't too much I
think the cavary engine is close to
good enough right so that's another
option we have if we can make it work
Looks like we are on the verge of making
being able to make it work. But what
about uh foreign engines and the money
and all the those questions? I don't
know about that. Um so the first
question you ask is should India go for
1,000 pages? No.
India should slowly phase out fighter
planes.
Look at the situation in West Asia.
There's a war going on. Look at the
situation in Ukraine. There's a war
going on.
Which weapons are effective? Are the
Americans flying fighter planes and
bombing targets and all that? Nothing.
Nothing. The war is being fought with
missiles and drones. Drones are unmanned
munitions.
They fly like planes. The Shahed drones
and whatnot. That's the future of
warfare. Why would you purchase a or or
build an expensive fighter plane, train
a person to fly it, invest millions of
dollars or cres, tens or maybe hundreds
of cres of rupees to train one person,
put the person in a fighter plane, you
fly it over very dangerous enemy
territory where there's a high chance of
getting shot down and lose the lose the
whole package. Why would you do that?
For the same amount of money, you can
build maybe 10,000 drones,
right? Or maybe
100 ballistic missiles.
So I think that makes more sense. Uh we
should certainly continue developing our
fighter jet, fighter engine program, jet
engine program and all that fighter jet
program, jet engine program.
Uh but those will be more valuable in
wars when when we have proper stealth
technology.
Uh yeah. So I think the in in in wars
in the current in the in the 21st
century fighter planes are relevant only
when you have suppressed all enemy air
defenses.
It's it's stupid to send human beings in
fighter planes over contested territory
in today's day and age. So I think India
should invest tremendously in drones and
missiles. Missiles of various kinds.
Whether it's cruise missiles, whether
it's supersonics, hypersonics,
ballistics
with various kinds of warheads, cluster
warheads. Learn from the Iranians. The
Iranians are far ahead of India when it
comes to ballistic missile technology.
It's clear now. We have the range 5 etc.
It's got whatever range 8,000 10,000 km
maybe more. We don't know. That's great.
But do we have cluster munitions,
cluster warheads?
Do we have the maneuvering warheads all
that? I think the Iranians are ahead of
us in these things. Learn from the
Iranians. India should uh give up
various fantasies. It has the fantasy of
having this massively powerful surface
fleet of ships and aircraft carriers.
That's a stupid fantasy. India should
invest in autonomous kill vehicles,
underwater kill vehicles and submarines.
When it comes to aerial warfare, invest
in drones.
flying munitions,
missiles of various kinds and do have
should we should have aircraft, fighter
aircraft, but those are to be used only
when the enemy's air defenses are
completely suppressed. That is the new
way of warfare and that's what India
should do.
Prattana, good to see you sir. Russians
cooperated in the arrest of these guys,
the American terrorists, the Ukrainian
terrorists. Yes, but this that raises
even more questions. What the hell is
the government of India doing? Is the
deal already done for the sale of
northeast? Okay, I don't know about any
deal for the sale of the northeast. But
the question that you asked, what the
hell is the government of India doing?
It's a very pertinent question.
What the hell is the government of India
doing? You have allowed Manipur to go to
the dogs. You have allowed allowed money
you have allowed Manipur to become a
disaster zone.
What kind of strategy or policy does the
government of India have? Who is what
kind of jokers are advising the
government of India when it comes to
Manipur?
I just don't get it.
I don't know even now what's happening.
We arrested this American guy and the
Ukrainian Ukrainian mercenaries, but
what are we going to do with this
arrest? Are we going to put them, you
know, release them on bail very soon?
Are we going to trade them off for this
this guy that nil or whatever guy the
Americans have arrested and then that's
it then Manipur goes back again to the
dogs or are we going to actually address
the core issues in Manipur and India's
far east there's a misaram issue also
okay I'm not sure what the government of
India is doing the government of India
has some interest in the kaladan multi
multimodal project which is like 78
years behind schedule and for that
little thing are we going to allow the
whole region to descend into chaos you
to cooperate with cookies. Is that the
deal? What is the deal? I don't get it.
There's no logic to what the government
of India is doing. Maybe they have some
logic, some brilliant logic of their
own.
But do they even understand the region?
Do they understand those
people in this region who are still on
India's side? But if they're treated
like this, you're going to push them
across the brink.
I mean how long can people suffer before
they say enough is enough
right? So I don't know what the deal is
the government of India has dropped the
ball when it comes to the northeast to
Manipur this industrial scale religious
conversion happening in Arunachal and
other parts of under the BJP government.
So I don't know what what we are doing
really I have no idea no idea
whatsoever.
Chetan says end of indigenous religion
is equal to end of Indian civilization
and when well it's happening right now
in India's far east it's happening in
Manipur for example it's happening in
Arunachal Pradesh 50 years ago in there
was not a single person who practiced
Abrahamic religion in Arunachal today it
looks like that's become a majority of
people when it comes to Manipur uh in
the 2011 census Hindus were were short
of the majority
But today I think Hindus would must be a
significant minority in Manipur now
significant minority
and the Hindus were the mateies
lots of mates lacks of them have in the
past few years converted to
Christianity. So we have essentially
currently the past 10 years or so we are
witnessing the further erosion of Indian
culture and civilization in India's far
east and that's happening in Punjab also
that's happening in various parts of
India also maybe in 50 years there'll be
no Hinduism left if things go the way
they are going right now under this
government
says ICBMs in megaton thermonuclear
bombs are a must for us G made a blunder
by agreeing to US demands to stop
further nuclear tests thoughts
India has been very aminable to various
kinds of American demands.
I think India should have done 2030
tests.
I think it's important. See the Chinese
it is said don't have sufficient nuclear
test data to produce better bombs.
That's what the Americans claim. India's
only done six tests. One in 1974 and
five in 1998.
So if you want to develop better bombs,
we need to perform more tests and gather
more data.
So um I think it it was best done during
Wajpay's time when Mr. Waji approved the
first you know the second batch of tests
in 1998 five tests we should have done a
few more maybe we should not have
stopped with five when the Pakistanis
did did their respon responded by doing
their test six tests we should have
conducted immediately several more
rounds of tests I would say today it's
very difficult to do it because of
American pressure but if there's a
nuclear test somewhere India should
immediately go ahead and do it
ICBMs are non-negotiable able. It's a
must for us. We should we India needs to
have ballistic missiles capable of
targeting any location on the planet.
It's important for our survival not
because we want to destroy the world but
because we want to have a universal
deterrent against anybody
and obviously with that we need to have
the right packages the right
deliverables which is thermonuclear and
other kinds of bombs. So we need to have
ICBMs. We need to have MIRV capability.
I think we have that now.
And not just five MIRVS per warhead per
per missile but 10 ideally also MV
maneuverable re-entry vehicles
and yeah various kinds of thermonuclear
and non-therrmonuclear warheads. So for
that you need to do some more testing.
So right now India is obviously not
going to be able to test unless somebody
else tests. If somebody else tests then
we should be ready to do it on as soon
as possible. I would say India needs at
least 20 20 more tests. Yeah. Just to
have a reasonable amount of data of
various kinds of yields and
configurations of uh nuclear weapons.
Mae talks says, "Do you think this war
started by Trump because he lost tariff
case in the US court and court ordered
to refund billions of dollars to US
importers?" Well, no. This war was
started by Trump. It was not started by
Trump. It was started by Israel.
The first strike in this war
was landed by was launched by Israel and
then the Americans joined in because as
their secretary of state Marco Rubio
says they knew that Israel was going to
launch an attack and we knew that if
Israel launches an attack, Iran will hit
at us will strike at us and that's why
we also struck at Iran. So this war was
started by Israel. The Israelis dragged
the US into it which tells you a lot
about the relationship. Who's the boss
in the relationship?
Israel is the boss of the US clearly
from the way things are going. Yeah,
that's actually what happened. Tommy
Verseti says Veretti Verseti. Okay, what
are the next what are the best next
steps for Iran taught in long term?
Short-term, medium-term, Iran, all it
has to do is survive.
It has to survive.
It has to survive in the sense that the
US needs it needs to make the US pull
out of the war
eventually. You see,
if the war continues without an Iranian
defeat, the Americans at some point at
some stage will have to pull out because
they can't just sustain a war like this
unless they seek to keep escalating
further and further boots on the ground
and so on, which is going to be a
disaster for the US and then they will
feel like they have to escalate even
more. So, what where does it end?
Uh anyhow so Iran what it needs to do is
it needs to survive. It needs from an
Iranian perspective, not that I want
this to happen, I don't want this to
happen, but from an Iranian perspective,
the straight of hormones needs to remain
closed,
right? So that the so that the global
sentiment against the war mounts so that
the global pain mounts there will be
pain for India, China, Japan, everybody,
all the nations whoever depend on oil
and uh hydrocarbons from hormos.
and the Iranians can allow certain
nations to keep u to to their ships to
transit hormones like it's allowing for
India. So yeah, so what Iran is doing is
exactly the right strategy from a game
theoretical perspective. Yeah, from a
great game theoretic perspective.
So next best steps, keep hormones
closed. It's bad for us but from Iran's
perspective, yes, keep hormones closed.
allow selected nations uh to to transit
hormos to have their tankers transit
hormos. Um keep on hitting out at the
American military bases in the region.
Keep on well doing what they're doing
with Israel
and keep fighting. The longer this war
lasts, the better it is for Iran, right?
They are also weaponizing time here
and eventually Israel is a small nation.
it may take too much damage you know and
they may either sue for peace or they
may take the next step uh which I hope
doesn't happen so that's the next best
steps for Iran
Spider-Man says if it is worse in
Manipur why news channels don't talk
about it well yesterday I was on
republic 9:00 p.m. yesterday
uh at least Arnab Gowami is one person
who is speaking about it
about what's happened about what's
happened like the the arrest of the
American guy American guy and the
Ukrainian mercenaries who are training
terrorists cookie terrorists so Arnab
was speaking about this I don't know
about other it looks like other news
channels are keeping quiet quiet about
this now you are asking something else
of of course that if the situation is
still bad in Manipur why are news
channels not speaking about
Because now
things are bad but the cookies they have
taken over large parts of Manipur.
Okay. In 2023 when you had this this
entire thing erupting the cookies were
doing ethnic cleansing
in places like Churachpur etc. they were
killing
and expelling non-cookies.
Now they have taken over all this
territory. Now the the the problems are
low inensity problems. It's not like
towns are burning, cities are burning,
but kidnappings are happening, murders
are happening, all that is happening.
But the media it looks for sensation
sensations elsewhere, right? It won't
keep covering Manipur for 2, three
years. For 3 years, it's been 3 years
now. Almost 3 years.
Almost 3 years. Yeah. So the media it
has this news cycle. They want to keep
covering other things and many of the
channels they have their own agendas
which I will not go into. Every channel
has its own agenda. They want to keep
certain things away from the news. They
don't want to cover certain things. Many
channels you should see where the
funding comes from that will tell you
what their agenda is and that sort of
thing.
Okay. News updates says because of you I
started loving geopolitics. You started
this trend in India when nobody is even
talking about this. Although on some
points I don't agree with you. I think
our government is too of CIA. We are
already a vasar. While it's impossible
for any two people to agree on anything,
that's fine. It's fine. You don't have
to agree with uh with me on everything.
You can of course feel free to disagree
and have your own opinions which is
good. Which shows that you are a
thinking person. And uh thank you very
much first of all for for your very nice
uh comment here. U see before me you had
geopolitical experts and analysts in
India. They used to call themselves
strategic affairs experts. The great
late Maru Fazar was one of them who I
used to personally follow. Sadly, he
passed away very recently. He is he was
he is one strategic affairs expert that
I used to follow personally when he used
to appear on times now and other
channels and typically well yeah he he's
a person who I greatly respected a true
Indian patriot left us too soon. So we
had strategic affairs experts in India
but this term geopolitics I suppose I
introduced it it in India and now
everybody calls themselves geopolitical
experts. Earlier it was strategic
affairs experts and
what I have striven to do is to explain
things as simply as possible. I believe
in simplifying things as as much as
possible. I don't want to show off and
use complicated terminology and try to
sound intelligent or whatever. I want to
make things as easy to understand as
possible and that's what I've striven to
do from day one and u I'm glad that uh
that it has helped you. I'm glad. So
thank you so much about India's
government being a stool of the CIA. we
are already a vasal but I'll tell you
what technologically we are a non-s
sovereign nation completely non-s
sovereign technologically we are also
deeply penetrated
at various levels in India
um
yeah so we have these issues
I'm going to re revisit India's
sovereignty once this war settles down
or stops hopefully yeah and we will
revisit the the revisit the question of
whether India is actually a sovereign
nation or not or are we partially
vasalized at least I will revisit this
sooner rather than later
thank you very much
prataradana says Trump cut healthcare
etc but asking Congress
for $200 billion for the war
well you see that's that's what the US
does that's what American presidents do
America's main export to the world is
war and obviously you have to fund wars.
wars are also profitable if you are um
US corporations that are part of the
military-industrial complex
and it's it's a pretty complex system in
which you may you you burn money to make
more money and your friends make money
and that sort of thing and that works in
a war that's going well but in this kind
of war where which is not going well for
the US you're going to have to ask
Congress for money so yes Trump has cut
healthcare and all that and he's asking
Congress for $200 billion.
Yep.
Power says, "Is is power a zero sum
game?" Power is not a game. Power is is
is is
what you seek in a game. Okay? Power is
something it's it's an objective. It's
something you want to acquire. It's
something you want to maximize.
Okay? It is it is what you are after in
the game. Power is not the game. Power
is like a substance. It's like cash.
It's like money.
It's what you are after the game. You
can configure a game in various ways
including zero sum games but not all
games are zero sum games. It depends on
the context. All right.
Mama bucket VFX. Good to see you. US
registers alien
go alien.go alias government domains.
Really? That's that's fascinating. Does
that happen? Let's see. Let's see. Let's
see. That's very interesting.
Um give me a second. Let me
let me see.
Alien.gov. Let's see. A L I E N. G O V.
What is that?
Aliens.gov domain registered after
Trump's vows. Trump wows UFO file, etc.
Very interesting. So maybe they're going
to launch a website with all their
disclosures about supposedly having
contacts with aliens. We'll see.
Interesting.
Prattana says, "Will GCC, Gulf
Cooperation Council countries jump into
the war
after the recent escalation? It still is
not in their interest to jump into the
war because Iran has demonstrated it is
more than capable
of fighting a war simultaneously against
eight countries.
That's the kind of homework Iran has
done. If the GCC nations jump into the
war, they're going to be targeted by by
Iran. Iran has stockpiles, very large
stockpiles. I don't know how many
ballistic missiles they have left, but
they have essentially an inexhaustible
supply of drones.
It's going to be a disaster for the GCC
nations.
This war will escalate further and the
GCC economies will be finished.
Their entire economic models will be
finished.
Doesn't make sense.
Ankita Kachab, good evening ma'am.
Fatahu has rendered Israel missile
defense systems ineffective. Failed to
intercept despite firing multiple times.
A big leap in the technology of warfare.
Absolutely. Absolutely big leap. It is
clear that Iran is a global leader in
ballistic missile technology and and and
missile technology and the kind of the
different types of warheads they have
designed and developed are remarkable.
So the first couple of weeks, 10 days or
a couple of weeks of the war, the the
Iranians u used up their old stockpiles
of missiles like like you know missiles
that are like 20 years old or 10 years
old or whatever and now that those are
exhausted and the objective was to make
the Israelis and Americans use up most
of their stockpiles of interceptor
missiles.
So that's been used up mostly. That's
why a lot of the Iranian missiles are
now hitting the targets way more
frequently than earlier. And that's why
Iran has to now launch less missiles per
day.
Now you have these newer missiles. Some
are solid fueled, some are liquid
fueled, mishaher, fatu, etc. Right? Um,
so these missiles now have very
interesting profiles if I can use the
word interesting for such a devastating
technology. You have missiles that are
making these doing these very complex
maneuvers while you know before they hit
the target. You have missiles that that
whose whose warheads over you know they
deploy a cluster of submunitions when a
single missile releases 60 different
submunitions. How on earth do you
intercept that? It's guaranteed that you
will fail. And even if it has just one
warhead and it's maneuvering, then you
may have to launch four, five, six
interceptors to perhaps have stand a
chance of intercepting that. And these
missiles not only maneuver, but they
release flares and whatnot, which
totally confuses the intercepting
missiles.
So essentially what you're saying is
entirely correct. The Iranian newer
ballistic missiles, they are almost
impossible to intercept. The Israeli
missile missile defense systems
seem to be helpless against these
missiles despite launching multiple
interceptors to take down one incoming
missile. And I'm wonder I'm curious. I'm
wondering and I don't mean to be
disparaging at all but I am wondering
what happened to Israel's iron beam
system.
uh one day before the war began, one day
before the Israelis began the war, Prime
Minister Modi was in Israel and the
Indian media was reporting that Israel
is offering the iron beam system to
India.
So what happened to the iron beam in the
context of the ongoing war?
Why hasn't Israel been able to use the
iron beam system that costs allegedly
less than $10 per shot to take down the
incoming missiles? What happened to the
iron beam?
Was it just hype?
Because because the iron beam is a
directed energy weapon. It's a laser. So
that acts essentially instantaneously at
the speed of light. So that should allow
you to intercept missiles even if they
are like less than a kilometers away.
So I really wonder what happened to all
of this. So it looks like um either the
iron beam system has been destroyed by
the Iranians or it was overhyped
but whatever the case be may be
the Iranian missiles have essentially
rendered the Israeli missile defense
systems more or less ineffective.
uh 3 weeks into the war. Absolutely.
Girishi says, "We received a tip off
from SVR channel about these peoples.
Russia has a major interest in Burma
military government which the US wants
to change." Well,
one hears that the that there was some
kind of tip tip off from Russian
intelligence to India
about these these foreigners, you know,
the American and the Ukrainians uh
crossing over from India into into
Myanmar and providing
terrorist training to cookie terrorists
and Myanmar is terrorists. Uh yeah,
that's what one hears. But it's not like
India did not know about this.
In 2025, the chief minister of Mizoram,
Shi Lu Humi, had stated
that more than 2,000
foreigners of US and UK origin
had come to Misoram
and were involved in these activities.
So it's not like it was unknown. India
was India knew about this for a very
long time. Looks like India has for some
reason in the past chosen to disregard
this
and I'm not making the story up. Shri
Aluaji said this. Do I have do I have a
link to that? Let me see. Give me a
second.
Uh let me see if I can find the link.
Mr. Luoma had made this statement in
2025. Give me a second. Hopefully I can
dig it out.
Lu Kumar, the chief minister of Mizam.
So what do we have?
Okay, this is a news report
from
2025.
Give me a second. Let me put this on the
screen.
So
here it is on the screen. This report is
from the 11th of March 2025. Today is
the 19th of March 2026. This is more
than one year ago. Misoram Chief
Minister Laluar says agents from the US
and UK are providing arms training to
terrorists in Myanmar.
He had previously called for whatever
extr territorial cookies unity.
Luoma was referring to the case of UK
national Daniel Nui arrested in June
2024 at the Ling Pui airport. He was
found possessing one live ammunition was
and was booked under whatever arm arms
act and he was later acquitted by a
court. So the Indian court acquitted
this guy who was providing terrorist
training to terrorists in Myanmar and he
was caught possessing live ammunition.
Why was this guy acquitted?
So this has been known to happen at
least since 2024 at least probably from
much before and if the chief minister of
an Indian state publicly said this it
means the government of India knew about
this.
So my question is why was no action
taken in 2024 in 2025?
Yeah you have these agents from the US
and UK doing this on a routine basis
apparently.
Why was the government of India sitting
in what was it waiting for
and why has this action been taken only
now for some reason and is this going to
be the the limits of the action that we
have taken and what about these people
who have been arrested will they also be
acquitted
big questions here I really don't know
what the government of India is doing
really honestly
Sergeant Skylan says USI Israel really
after Pakistan or just lip service?
Are the US and Israel really after
Pakistan? Do you think Israel and the US
are see US for the US Pakistan is a
valuable asset.
Why will be the US why will the US be
after Pakistan or against Pakistan?
Pakistan is a super valuable asset for
the US. The US can get the Pakistanis to
do all kinds of dirty work for them
while the Americans keep their hands
clean. Who was David Headley,
American terrorist? He's one US national
who was a terrorist. But who are all
these other Pakistani terrorists? They
are Pakistanis. They do terrorism.
It's funded and financed by the US.
It's aimed at India, but the US keeps
its hands clean. The Pakistanis do all
the dirty work. Why will the Americans
go after Pakistan?
And about Israel, you are wondering
whether Israel is going to go go after
Pakistan. Let me show you something once
again. I did this earlier, but let me
show this again.
The Pakistanis launched an air strike on
an Afghanistan on a on a building in
Kabul which killed 400 patients who were
undergoing drug rehab rehabilitation.
This is an account from Israel. It's
based out of Israel.
Okay. It is the unofficial account of
Mossad, which maybe it's not Mossad,
maybe it is, but it's unofficial, but
it's definitely based out of Israel.
And this account is claiming, it's
supporting the Pakistani terrorist
activities, the Pakistani air strike
that killed 400 patients. These guys are
claiming the Kabul site was not a drug
rehab center. It was a Taliban weapons
and ammunition storage site. How does
the Mossad Ortis account know about
that? And why are the supporting
Pakistan?
Pakistan's armed forces launched
operation Gazab blah blah blah overnight
carrying out precision air strikes
against Afghan Taliban regime facilities
tied to terrorism. So this Mossad
account alleged Mossad account is
claiming that Afghanistan is a bunch of
terrorists and Pakistanis are people who
are fighting terrorism. So when Israel
has this approach towards Pakistan, do
you think they will go go after
Pakistan? I have said this for a long
I've asked this question for a long
time.
Pakistan is a US vasal. It's a US asset,
valuable asset for the US. The US
offers Israel unconditional support
which means the US is Israel's
unconditional ally. So US Pakistan this
relationship, USI Israel that
relationship. What is the relationship
between Israel and Pakistan? That's a
big question I've always asked.
And by the way, the name Israel does
figure
in
any informed discussion about Manipur.
Tanmay Mukharji has become a new member.
Well, thank you so much Tanmai G.
Welcome to the channel's membership.
Thank you.
Brianka Biswis says, "Visited VECC
today. The scale and complexity of those
cyclones and accelerators is
overwhelming. I'm also working on a
small project on GM detectors.
Okay. What's VCC? I don't remember. Let
me um Google that. What is variable
energy cyclone
cyclone center? Is it? Let me see. Is it
variable energy cyclone center? Let me
see. Variable energy cyclone center.
VCC. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. I knew it. Yay.
It is in Kolkata. Is it in SINP? Saha
instead of nuclear physics.
Okay. Nice. So, the cyclone is well a
pretty ancient instrument. It's one of
the first ever designs for a particle
accelerator.
and you have a magnetic field which
causes your electrons or your your
charged particles to go in circles and
then you yeah you pulse it and you have
a certain frequency and you use that to
have it go and smash into a target that
sort of thing it's something you learn
in college I suppose in basic nuclear
physics college
um so cyclones are actually pretty
simple instruments okay uh so VCC is
variable energy cyclone center probably
at SIP in Kolkata
or maybe associated with SIP Saha
Institute of Nuclear Physics. Uh what's
a gem detector? What's a gem detector?
Let's find out what's a gem detector.
GM detector, gallium, etc. Is it a gas
electron multiplier detector,
gaseous ionization detector? Okay. Okay.
You're working on a small project on GM
detectors. Gas electron mult. Yeah, this
is I haven't heard these terms for a
very long time. Interesting.
Interesting. Particle physics, nuclear
physics. So, yeah, I'm glad. So, my
point is this, if you're a student, is
very inspiring to actually visit one of
these centers and see the instruments
that you've been reading about, but you
finally get to see one. It's even better
if you can see one in operation. So, in
India, we have a few of these
accelerators. You have a cyclone in
Kolkata. You have something called a
pelletron in the Tata Institute of
Fundamental Research in Mumbai. I'm not
sure if we have any other accelerators
in India.
Uh but yes, it's always it's always fun.
It's always inspiring as a student to
visit one of these uh centers and see
the actual instrument that you've been
study been studying and reading about.
And you're also working on a small
project on gas uh GM detectors. So
outstanding. keep going and uh all the
best. Thank you for sharing this very
interesting story.
Voyagi says, "What are the lessons of
caution that China will or would have
learned from the 2026 Iran war?" Like
some analysts are saying that China
knows that American weapons can can at
will
air bomb without being detected. Okay.
What are the lessons China will be
learning from the ongoing war, Iran war?
One lesson
that
you need large numbers
of cheap munitions, drones.
China has the industrial capability
capacity to manufacture millions of
drones. Millions. Not thousands, not
tens of thousands, not hundreds of
thousands, millions of drones. And they
will do this. They will manufacture and
stockpile millions of drones.
That guarantees victory. Guarantees
victory. Number two, missiles,
ballistics, cruise, missiles, and so on.
Third,
take out the interceptors. Take out the
THAAD,
take out the Patriot systems.
that will render the the defenses of the
Americans blind.
Fourth,
take do what Iran is doing, but at the
take it to the next level. Iran is
launching volleys of missiles and
drones, waves of missiles and drones.
The Chinese can take it to the next
level by launching saturation strikes.
launch a a wave of a 100,000 drones.
Then launch another wave of 100,000
drones, then launch another wave of
100,000 drones and mix. And while the
drones are landing, send 500 ballistic
missiles or cruise missiles. The Chinese
have the industrial
capacity to produce these things at
scale.
What can America, what can anyone do
when faced with that sort of onslaught?
It will take out aircraft carriers. It
will take out entire islands. It'll take
out all the island chains. It can take
out all the American ships. Everything.
It's it's it's a mathematical certainty
that if you launch enough projectiles,
they will go through defenses. That's
what the Chinese will do when it comes
to Taiwan. The Chinese can't take Taiwan
intact. They know that.
But they want Taiwan. Maybe that's what
they will do, right?
And the Chinese also know
that if a war happens, the Americans
will will will will target China's
oil fields, strategic oil reserves,
industrial areas, and so on. And the
Chinese will have to find ways of
safeguarding that. So the Chinese have
seen what the American strategy
strategies and tactics are,
what has worked, what's not worked, and
they can see what the Iranian strategies
are and what's worked and the Chinese
can take it to the next level. So this
these these are the lessons of war,
caution,
etc. that the Chinese will be in the
process of learning and that's something
India also has to learn, right? and the
importance of having high quality
satellites, military satellites,
satellite imagery and and and satellite
positioning systems. India doesn't have
a satellite position position
positioning system anymore. The
government of India has allowed NAI to
become defunct defunct.
We had something called Navic, right? A
regional satellite positioning system.
The government of India has allowed it
to become defunct. It'll take at least a
year or two for us to have an
operational u satellite positioning
system once again. What if there's a war
between us and and China in the
meanwhile or us and Pakistan? What
happens? I wonder what happens.
Wonderful.
Praradana says it's amazing how many of
our YouTubers are on the MOSAD payroll.
Only YouTubers, not journalists.
I don't know. I'm just speculating.
Amazing, isn't it?
WBKT says, "Your opinion on on MC21 and
PD14 engine tech sovereignty." I don't
know what these things are, but I can
find out. What is MC21 and PD14? MC21.
What's that? Yakovv.
It's a Yakovv aircraft.
Um, are we manufacturing it in India? We
uh let me just see variance and
operators etc. Proposed variance. Is
there anything to do with India
India?
Okay. I don't know. Maybe there'll be
something to do with this in India. The
Sukoy super super Sukoy thing we were
going ahead with, right? Are we also
going ahead with the Yakovv MC uh 21?
What's the engine? Is it the PD14?
Okay. PD14 engine. PD14 engine. Is India
going to operate this or buy it? No
idea.
Uh so I'm not aware of whether India has
any plans to acquire this aircraft,
manufacture it in India, maybe
manufacture the engine. I don't know
about this.
um if we do good as long as we are able
to manufacture it in-house in India and
about the engine if we can acquire the
technology if we can purchase the
technology great for us but I don't know
if we have any plans for that
Jooshi says what seems to be the
direction of the US Iran war now Iran
leadership seems to get decimated but
they are targeting energy sites and not
US bases anymore ceasefire soon no
ceasefire soon no ceasefire soon Iran
doesn't want a ceasefire Iran has given
terms for for a ceasefire.
Iran is given the kind of terms that
will never be acceptable to the US which
essentially is a way of saying we don't
want a ceasefire. Iran says that the US
has to pay huge compensation to Iran.
huge compensation and Iran India and the
US has to pass a bill or law in Congress
that prevents the Americans from ever
waging war against Iran again and
America has to withdraw from all the
military military installations it had
in the Gulf region and I suppose
something else as well. These are the
terms some of the terms that the
Iranians have put forth for a ceasefire.
These are never going to be accept
acceptable to the US. There's no
ceasefire coming anytime soon.
I hope I'm completely wrong, but I don't
see it happening. I hope I'm wrong. I'll
be happy if I'm wrong, but I don't see a
ceasefire coming. Iran's leadership is
decimated. Doesn't make any difference
to Iran. Iran is going to be just fine.
They're going to have new leaders,
perhaps more capable leaders, definitely
more hardline leaders.
Okay? In India, we feel that a nation
can only have two or three leaders. No,
a nation can produce thousands of
leaders.
In a nation like India, you have
thousands, tens of thousands of very
highquality leaders
who are never allowed to rise up the
whose potential is suppressed by the
existing elite. It's called the
phenomenon of elite over production in
Iran. That problem is being solved by
the Americans and the and the Israelis.
So the fresh young blood is going to
come up now. It's like what you have in
in warfare in battle on on battle. What
happens when you have a battle going on
and your dealer gets killed? Your
commander of your of your regiment or or
or your brigade gets killed. You have an
on the spot field promotion. The most
capable person is made the leader
immediately, the commander.
And these field promotions, they
typically give you the best leaders.
Field promotions happen under
under terrible stress. When you are
being shot at where your commander has
been killed, that's when you have to
elevate the most capable person to the
position of leadership. Not the most
senior person necessarily, the most
capable person so that you can all
survive and you can win the battle. So
that's when the best leadership emerges.
Iran is in that position now where they
will have to promote the most capable
people, not the most senior people.
That's where new leaders truly emerge.
Iran is going to be fine from that
perspective. The leadership is
decipated. Makes no difference. They're
going to be fine. They're targeting
energy sites. They're targeting all the
all the weak points and pain points of
their enemies. They're doing a great job
of that. Yeah, they've done their
homework.
Rishab Rashit says, "Good evening.
What's is scope X
and Bill Gates trying to go to do about
solar geoengineering? Is it really
related to southern weather change?" I
don't know about scopeex, but let's find
out.
Scopeex.
What is ScopeEx? It's a game on Steam.
It's a game on Steam. But is there
something else to Scopex? Scopeex.
Um, SC suspended. Oh, Scopex.
No, no, no. I'm not playing a YouTube
video. No, no, no, no, no.
Scope X with a capital P. What is that?
Let's see.
What is this?
Uh suspended Harvard stratospheric
geoengineering research project.
Scopeex Harvard stratospheric
stratospheric.
Okay. What is this?
It's something that's suspended.
So I don't know. I'm not going to open
the thing and start doing research about
this and try and understand what it is.
Looks like it's suspended. Um, so yeah,
I don't know. It's a suspended project.
It had something to do with Howard, not
Bill Gates. So I don't really know. So
yeah, I don't know.
Pratik Kumar Royce says, "Did you see
Durand the Revenge? It came out today. I
haven't seen it yet. I do plan to vis to
to watch the movie.
I would not mind watching it uh very
soon."
Um, okay. I hear I heard there's a scene
in which they show that the Pakistani
nuclear codes are under Israeli control.
That'll be interesting. That'll be
interesting if that's the case. I
haven't seen it. I shall watch it uh at
some point in time and I shall share my
views at that point once I watch it.
Okay.
Barat M. Kulkarnney says, "US gains from
GCC oil loss but loses petro dollar
inflow kind of." Yeah.
Um
yeah, so the US is said to be at least
on paper the world's largest producer of
of oil. And if the GCC nations are are
are impacted badly like they are right
now and they uh and their exports fall
because of the closure or partial
closure the selective closure of the
state of Hormuz then long-term the US
will gain if this situation persists for
months then the US exports will rise
significantly and make up for the loss
of exports from Hormos. So the US will
benefit in that p from that perspective
but
the petro dollar inflow will be lost. So
then the oil that the Americans will
will sell will obviously be sold in in
dollars. Yes. Uh but long-term if the
Iranians are able to prevail then it
doesn't make any sense for the GCC
nations to in the future long-term keep
selling oil in US dollars. If the
Iranians prevail and destroy the
American bases permanently in the region
which means the Americans can't arm
twist the GCC nations in that case
things will change and the petro dollar
system could collapse in that case.
Surabi says watched Durand 2. The movie
is the goat. It has exposed Pakistan and
its operators in India like no other. It
showed ISI ties with Israel. Explain. I
can only explain once I watch it. I
haven't seen it. I don't know what the
ties with Israel are but it's very
interesting. I'm hearing this Israel
angle.
Very interesting. Very interesting.
I shall watch it at the earliest but I
haven't seen it so I can't explain
anything at this point.
Push says Japan and South Korea are
under permanent US military occupation.
Indeed. Indeed. Like I have explained to
the world still they have better infra
education etc. Does becoming a US
benefit India that way? I have answered
this question so many times. Let me
answer it again.
Japan
until the m until the early 1980s was
the world's fastest growing large
economy. It was the world's second
largest economy.
It was on track to surpass the US as the
Okay, at that time Japan was a very high
income nation. Then the Americans
imposed the Plaza Accords on Japan. They
tweaked the Japanese economy and Japan
went into a very slow decline and today
Japan is a middle inome nation. It's no
longer a high income nation. Would you
believe it?
And Japan's total fertility rate has
declined drastically.
It has become so bad that in a 100 years
there may be no Japanese people left.
So temporarily for a few years
you can enjoy your better infrastructure
educa education education system in
Japan it's high quality but it is
extremely stressful for people and it's
one of the contributing factors of Japan
having such a low TFR today
okay so long-term Japan is finished
sadly tragically
that's what happens when you're a vasal
temporarily through three generations
four five generations You enjoy
vasalhood. You have a high quality of
living. You have great infrastructure.
But 40, 50 years down the line, your
children
are the last of of your lineage.
Or your grandchildren are the last of
your lineage. After that, there's no
lineage left. You you're done. You're
finished. Your bloodline is over. All
the bloodlines are over. Then the
Americans will bring in immigrants into
Japan and they will take over Japan.
People from Bangladesh, Pakistan,
African nations. etc. In a 100 years,
there'll be the new Japanese. South
Korea, same disaster, TFR loss.
South Korea is not producing babies
anymore. In 100 years, there'll be no
South Koreans left. Do you want that for
India? Does that somehow benefit India?
Becoming a US vasal.
While you are useful,
you will enjoy some perks of vasalhood.
But sooner or later, when the overlord
decides your time is up, your time is
up. You're finished.
Anabil Sarkar says, "Have you watched
Durand 2? Love your content." Thank you
for loving my content. I haven't watched
it yet, but I shall watch it as soon as
I can. Okay. Prataradana says,
"Government lost the support of a lot of
young people. Example, FE in India,
defense, technology,
independence, ISO, Manipur, Bangladesh's
education, UGC issues. Hopefully they
wake up. Hopefully they wake up.
Hopefully they wake up. Yes.
uh fake in India
uh defense
and technological independence or lack
of independence. Yeah, ISRO India has
just allowed ISRO to slip.
The government has
dropped the ball when it comes to space
space exploration.
It's not some luxury activity space
exploration. It is the future of
humanity.
If we don't invest in space today, then
our future generations will be left
behind like nothing you can imagine.
So space the government doesn't seem to
think it's important. ISRO is exists as
a luxury project. It looks like for this
government manipur disaster beyond
imagination.
Bangladesh is tens of millions of
Bangladesh all over India. Maybe
increasing
education UGC. Yeah. all these issues.
So I hope the government of India wakes
up. I hope they wake up.
Pratip Kumar Roy says what is this World
Economic Forum? The WF is this uh
economic organization controlled at the
end of the day by the Americans.
uh that has the objective of uh
uh helping nations with see there is the
IMF there's the world bank there's the
world economic forum they all play
different roles the IMF and world bank
issue loans to countries and vasalize
those countries economically
and obviously the world bank and IMF are
owned by the Americans at the end of the
day okay whether directly or indirectly
they are owned by the Americans
sometimes it's very indirect but at the
end of the day they are owned by the
Americans sim similarly The WF
is, you could say, a manifestation of
the deep state that that owns the
Americans.
And the WF its objective is to penetrate
the cabinets of various countries
and to shape the economic policies and
the futures of various countries that it
is it's able to penetrate.
So essentially, it's another
vasalization tool that the Americans or
the deep state have. Okay.
Kumar says how what or how can we
sabotage US infra and important projects
we don't talk about such things no we
don't discuss such things we don't do
such things either
Jose Fashik says can we make straight
form like a choke point in the Indian
Ocean
well you can't create geographical choke
points you can only uh leverage them or
use them if you have them nearby. So
let's take a look at the geography
around India.
So let's go to the map. H so in our
neighborhood we have at least three
choke points. Okay. So this is India and
the Indian Ocean region. Okay. Now what
choke points do we have? So one is
Hormuz of course which is in our
neighborhood. It is not far from India.
So you could say it's it's part of our
uh area of interest. That's a straight
of Hormos. Secondly, we have Babal
Mandib and the Indian Navy has operated
in this region to ensure that there is
no piracy. So this this strait is
another geographical choke point. It's
called the Bab al-mand strait. That's
between the Red Sea and the Gulf of
Aden. Then we have the straight straight
of Malaka over here. That's another very
important choke point. Then you also
have the sunda strait right? Where is
the sunda straight? This one here.
What is this uh straight called?
Uh whatever it's called. This is another
another choke point that is an
alternative to the straight of hor to
the straight of Mala.
So these are three choke points in our
neighborhood
and India if it wants has the ability to
blockade all three if the Indian Navy is
capable enough. Indian navy is
definitely capable enough to blockade
Mala
which means that it can also blockade
hormos if it wants and even Bab al-mand
the Indian Navy is the most powerful
navy in this entire region right so if
required we can do this but ideally we
don't want to ever do these things we
should not be in a position where we
have to take such measures but we can if
we have to so how do you blockade a
straight or a choke point you use n you
can use naval firepower. You can use
submarines. You can lay mines there. You
can use missiles. You can use aircraft
anti-access area denial strategies and
so on. You can create A2A bubbles.
That's another thing. That's how you
blockade. That's multiple ways of
blockading choke point.
Aw. Okay. No question. Thank you very
much. AW. Thank you. Kakashi says
Shabbah Sharif in the US met pro-Israel
Jewish lobby who praised him for
removing Israel critical clauses in OIC
statements also what is Mossad doing in
the in India's far east or northeast
yes so
I remember that when Aim Munir
was in the US
he has made multiple visits to the US
met with Donald Trump right um the
American warlord.
So when Shabbat when Aim Munir was in
the US, the Pakistani embassy or
consulate whatever it was had organized
a dinner in the honor of Aim Mun, their
dictator and one of the attendees was an
Israeli military officer. So there was
an Israeli military presence at least
one person at least maybe more in that
dinner hosted by Pakistani diplomats
Pakistani embassy or consulate in honor
of the Pakistani dictator
that was reported by the media.
Okay. Now I don't know about the story
about Shabb Sharif meeting Jewish lobby
or whatever but uh not very surprising.
I I am personally not surprised if that
is the case if if that really happened.
Um what is Mossad doing in the
northeast? Well, I think the government
of India needs to look into whatever the
Mossad is doing in the northeast.
See the disaster in Manipur, it is
caused by cookie terrorists. Okay,
these cookie terrorists, these cookies,
these cookies are not Indian, they are
not Burmese. They come from God knows
maybe the Yunan region that's currently
occupied by China.
They are not Burmese. They don't speak
the Burmese language. They don't
practice Burmese culture. They don't
respect Burmese culture. They don't
practice Indian culture or respect
Indian culture.
They are handin glove with
foreign elements whether it is the
church, whether it is various
intelligence agencies.
Okay.
These cookies, some of them claim to be
Jewish. we are one of the Jew lost
Jewish tribes or something and Israel
has been offering these individuals
citizenship of Israel.
So they so Israel, Israeli rabbis or
whatever, they baptize these people into
Judaism
and then once they become Jewish, once
they're officially Jewish, they are
given Israeli citizenship. Then they are
settled in conflict zones in Israel
where there is high levels of conflict
between um Israel and the Palestinians.
So So these cookies are settled in those
areas.
Okay. And there's been allegedly racism
against the cookies in Israel. And uh at
least one cookie individual was um was
murdered for whatever reason. Uh that
sort of thing. And the cookies claim to
be Jews, but they have no Jewish DNA
whatsoever. Okay. And cookies eat pork
and dogs. They eat dog meat. They eat
pork meat, pig meat. So how can people
who love eating pork become Jews? I
wonder. But anyway there seems to be
some utility that they have. Okay.
Um yeah and when this violence broke out
in Manipur the cookies terrorizing the
natives there was a lot of support for
these cookie terrorists allegedly from
Israel. Maybe it is the Israeli cookies
who were supporting it these cookies
possibly. But there's at least one
instance
where there was a group of Indian
influencers who were invited to visit
Israel.
Okay. Including an Indian politician.
And the Israeli government
brought a cookie rabbi to meet these
Indian influencers to explain Israel's
position on the Manipur issue or
whatever. Now that is direct blatant
interference in the internal affairs of
India by Israel that one incident.
So yeah it's a good question what is
Israel's involvement if any in Manipur
in the disaster that's happening in
Manipur ongoing you know on in the
ongoing disaster in Manipur and I think
the government of India also needs to
look into this very carefully.
An
says why is Jinism despite being ancient
Vic religion not that widespread as
compared to its contemporaries Hinduism
and Buddhism
these things eb and flow there was a
time when Buddhism was widespread across
the subcontinent wasn't it was the major
religion or the major branch of Hinduism
the branch it was the major branch of
the dharmic umbrella within the
subcontinent Buddhism
it was elevated to that status
artificially by Ashok Kamaria
and so it it was prevalent for a few
centuries and then it naturally declined
in in in any civilization changes
happened naturally there was there were
times when Janism was a very big deal uh
one of Ashok's grandsons I forget his
name he built tens of thousands of Jane
temples in various parts of the
subcontinent. So Janism was prevalent
for a long time. It was very prevalent
in in the southern parts of India for a
long time and then eventually it also
declined but it's not gone anywhere.
It's still there. There are fewer people
who practice janism today. Maybe in
2,000 years there'll be way more. Who
knows? We never know. These things eb
and flow naturally. Sometimes there is
an artificial component to that when you
have imperial patronage for one of the
branches of dharma. For example,
Buddhism got imperial patronage from
from Ashoke and that's why it spread so
much. So there are various reasons for
this. I don't know specifically why
Janism declined and it has only few lakh
or few million followers today. I don't
know exactly specifically what happened
but these are natural
civilizational processes.
Pratip Kumar Roy says just realize the
Bohemian Grove owl statue altar is
similar to the original Illuminati
symbol.
Okay, I have no understanding of these
things but let us see what's the
original illumin. Okay, first of all,
what's the Bohemian grove owl? Bohemian
grove owl statue.
What is that? Let us see what it looks
like.
Okay, this sort of thing is it? Yeah, it
looks rather woo creepy
this thing here.
Okay, so this is the alleged uh thing.
This is the alleged picture of the
alleged statue. Now, what's the original
Illuminati symbol? Let's see.
Original Illuminati symbol.
What is that? So, that's a pyramid thing
with an I, right? But is there an owl
somewhere? Is this the thing?
Okay. Okay. So I am not any kind of
expert in these matters so I don't
really know but uh okay interesting
interesting thank you for sharing this
interesting piece of information sir.
Prar Dhana says government now allegedly
starting the DME pilot project really
dimethile ether really let's see
uh a week after we discussed that last
time over here on this show I think the
last episode or the one before that
dimethile ether India
um okay
very good
do we have any news.
So 3 hours ago some news has come out.
We discussed this about a week or so
ago, didn't we on this channel? So it's
possible that somebody in the government
may be watching this
show. Ask a show. It's very
possible.
Okay.
So it suddenly has emerged in in the
last 3 to 5 days.
So I discussed dimethile ether on this
show in one of the last one or two
episodes. I I didn't come up with it.
Somebody in my audience pointed out that
DME is a great potential fuel source. So
that's why it was discussed by me at the
behest of one of my viewers. It was
discussed on this channel I think a week
or so ago and now in the past 3 to five
days it's in the news that it's emerging
as a great alternative to LPG. Well, I'm
glad. I'm glad. I'm glad. I thank
whoever my viewer was who pointed this
out and I thank whoever in the
government has noticed it.
All right. I'm I'm pleased. I'm happy.
Good.
Anur Das says US getting pounded.
India's chances of sovereignty high.
Let's let's not count our chickens
before they hatch.
US is getting pounded
but we are still technologically very
badly dependent on the Americans.
Whether it is airplanes, whether it is
uh Boeing,
whether it is um automobile engines,
whether it is laptops, whether it is
phones, mobile phones, whether it is
semiconductors,
whether it's the internet, whether
that's social media. We are very very
badly dependent on the United States.
Our people, our government has simply
just dropped the ball on these things.
We are one of the biggest importers of
arms in the world.
But overall I would say that the US is
getting pounded by Iran and the chances
of our sovereignty slipping further are
lower. Sure that that that much is good.
Yes.
Yet user says the Indian rupee keeps on
falling even against small countries
like Thailand, Sri Lanka. Do you think
it's bad for us given we are
increasingly an import based economy?
Is it bad for us?
It's good if you're an export based
economy. If you're an import-based
economy, it's not good for you.
Yeah, the government needs to do
something to shore it up. Maybe it's a
maybe it's a strategy to have the Indian
rupee decline. Forget about the prestige
of having a high value currency, but
maybe it's beneficial in some way. I'm
not sure what it is.
Uh but yeah the Indian rupee is right
now what 93 or something as a compared
to the dollar. It was 90 a week ago. So
it seems to be dropping compared to the
dollar. The dollar can be manu can be
manipulated artificially. We know that
the Americans do it all the time. But
what's the current rate? Indian rupee to
US dollar.
Uh let's let's uh do it the other way
around.
US dollar to Indian rupee.
93. Sorry. You see 93
and 21st of February it was 90.73.
So that's a month ago, right?
Okay. A month ago it was 90.73. Now it's
93.14. So you can see it's it's
declining. Sure. Yeah. Is that overall
bad for India? I'm not really sure. It
will have to there are lots of factors
that you have to consider into that. But
overall yes, there is a decline.
significant visible decline.
Al- Kashikari says, "How come the US
overlooked Iran's chokepoint
weaponization strategy? Is this
overconfidence or stupidity on their
path?" You know, overconfidence and
stupidity are essentially two sides of
the same coin. It's the same thing. Uh
overconfidence, it can be a symptom of
stupidity.
Uh so what's happened? See when the
Americans got into this war at the
behest of Israel
looks like they were operating under the
assumption that the war will be over in
a couple of days.
They thought I think it looks like they
thought that if they assassinate Kame
and the top leadership the Iranians will
come begging for
a ceasefire and they'll be they'll come
begging for surrender. We want to
surrender. stop the war. That's what the
Americans imagined most likely.
They had no idea what was coming for
them.
They had not dreamt in a thousand years
that Iran would put up the kind of fight
it is putting up, right? They thought
it'll be like Venezuela. We go in, we
take out Kamei, we kill their
leadership, we drop a few tons of bombs
and that's it over. We get what we want.
So that is stupidity multiplied by our
confidence.
Yeah. Isn't it? Yeah.
Nadit warm says how probable percentage
wise is it for this war to go nuclear? I
would say right now I would give it a
very low probability maybe like 1% or
2%. Right? the longer it goes on. See,
the question is who is more likely to
resort to the use of nuclear weapons? Is
it the US? Is it Israel? There's only
two nuclear powers involved in this.
Pakistan isn't and Pakistan is a is not
really nuclear power. It's a it's a it's
a custodian of American nuclear weapons
now. So, it's the either the US or
Israel that could take this war into the
nuclear dimension. The US
will not see any of it m its major red
lines crossed. All the major red lines
have already been crossed essentially
for the US. All their military bases in
the region have been targeted
significantly maybe completely destroyed
some of them. Who knows? We don't know.
It is being the news is being
suppressed. So we don't know.
So those red lines are crossed and the
Americans obviously haven't responded in
a nuclear manner. Obviously not because
see US territory is not being threatened
and so on. So the US is less likely
significantly less likely to even think
about nuclear weapons.
But Iran, Israel, Israel, Israel is
being targeted by the Iranians on a
daily basis in retaliation to whatever
the Americans and Israelis are doing.
And the Iranians are able to now
hit
Israeli targets way more frequently
and precisely than in the first couple
of weeks of the war. even though the
Iranians are now launching less missiles
per day, but still the missiles are
going through because the Israelis have
run out of of most of their
interceptors. So the longer this
continues,
the more pain Israel is going to have to
take. And if the Israelis escalate
somewhere and the Iranians hit the Muna
for example, the negative nuclear
uh res research facility,
then that's a red line, significant red
line for Israel. If the Iranians are
able to take out Israel's missile silos,
because Israel is a small territory,
if they want to launch nuclear missiles,
there's only a few places where their
silos are, and they're quite visible if
you know where to look. If Iran takes
that out, then Israel could get
desperate and maybe launch a nuclear
strike. So I think right now, as of
today, the percentage probability of of
this war going nuclear maybe like 1 or
2%. And I hope it doesn't go above that.
But overall, I would say Israel is way
more likely than the US to think about
using nuclear weapons.
Roarana says, "Jenz is consuming a lot
of pro-Israel US media. Iran is being
portrayed as the fun funer of terrorism
in the world. Can you recall how
terrorism game started for the youth of
Bat?
Well, how did this entire business of
terrorism start?
It is asymmetric warfare that was turned
against nations. Oh,
when I was a kid, the out. When I
was kid,
the
the Soviets invaded Afghanistan on
Christmas Day 1979. In response to that,
very quickly, the Americans started
training the mujahedin in Pakistan and
the mujahedin were then pushed over into
Afghanistan
with indirectly
supplied American arms, ammunition and
funds via Pakistan.
And the mujahedin fought the Soviets
over a period of a decade and they
learned all these unconventional
guerrilla tactics of guerrilla warfare
tactics, asymmetric warfare tactics and
so on and they they eventually uh
outlasted the Soviets and the Soviets
retreated withdrew from Afghanistan 1988
or 89 whichever year it was and then
Pakistanis realized we have this we have
overproduced mujahedines
now let's take this over capacity we
have and funnel it into Kashmir.
So that is the start of terrorism in
Kashmir. But in the 1980s the Pakistanis
were already using terrorism in in
Punjab in Punjab right. So that's kind
of where terrorism starts using
asymmetric guerrilla warfare tactics
against unarmed people civilian people
civilians of India
terrorizing the people trying to destroy
this their way of life that is
terrorism. So Pakistan is the originator
of terrorism. When I was a kid, like now
I say I in the 80s I lived in Europe and
there was this uh there was talk of
terrorism. There was this li civil war
going on in Lebanon at the time. Okay.
General Michel was one of the guys and
there was this Abu Nidal group
that was one of the original Middle
Eastern terrorist groups. Let's see.
Abu Nidal group.
Abu Nidal organization founded
in 1974 Palestinian militant group. So
they were from their perspective freedom
fighters but eventually the Americans in
the 1980s
designated them as terrorists.
But the game of terrorism essentially
starts with Pakistan.
Okay. It starts with Pakistan.
So the Abu Dhabal organization was
fighting for the so-called independence
of so-called Palestine. Okay. Maybe from
their perspective, from their worldview,
they were correct. They were fighting
for independence. Okay. Um but what
Pakistan did visav Indian Punjab and and
Kashmir
was terrorism.
They pushed in terrorists to strike at
civilians.
So that is how the game of terrorism
started worldwide. Started with
Pakistan. Essentially
Iran what
what does Iran have to do with
terrorism? Iran obviously seems to be on
good terms with Hamas and Hamas is a
terrorist organization. Well, if you
want to draw parallel, the US is is on
good terms with Pakistan, the global
epicenter of terrorism and the Americans
funded and financed Pakistan terrorism
for decades. So if Ian is a supporter of
terrorism in some sense, then the US is
a far bigger supporter of terrorism in a
lot of other senses,
right? But you have to learn how to
think in order to in order to be able to
see this parallels.
Gen Z, what can I say?
They'll consume whatever media is
available to them, right? You can't
blame them. Can't blame them. So yeah,
even the Indian media is portray a lot
of the Indian media, much of the Indian
Indian media is portraying Iran in that
manner.
Kakashi says if India is sovereign then
why doesn't the US oppose India publicly
like it does Iran, Russia, China,
CUV, CU whatever else
is India anti-imperialist like this
countries? No. India is trying to walk
the tight rope. India is trying to
balance things out like every weak all
weak countries do that they try to
balance things out. They want to be on
all sides. They want to be
multi-aligned. They also want to be on
good terms with the Americans.
Right?
So India is not doing the kinds of
things that Russia or China are doing.
Being totally upright and completely
uncompromising when it comes to American
attempts to infiltrate them.
When Xiinping came to power, it is said
that lots of Chinese
compromised Chinese officials were
rounded up and taken care of. Russia
does that from time to time. Anyone who
is in the least way compromised by the
Americans is taken out, is taken care
of.
Does India do that?
So why would the US oppose India the
same way it opposes Russia or China?
Right? India is perfectly fine with
being infiltrated and penetrated by the
Americans at various levels. India is
perfectly fine with that. So, so then
you are absolutely right to ask whether
India is genuinely sovereign. Right now,
India is on my list of sovereign
nations.
I made that list.
I revised I made that list in 2024. I
revised it on the day Iran was attacked
by the Americans and the Israelis.
But I have not revised or or or
revisited India's position on the list.
Once this war is over, hopefully soon I
shall revisit the entire list and the
entire system of rankings. And if the
war doesn't end in a few months, I'll do
it anyway. Right? But your question is
very relevant. Is India genuinely
sovereign? I think it's a very good
question to ask at this point in time.
Krishant Boraloy says, "It's my 20th
birthday. Wish me happy birthday. Big
fan from Assam. Love from Assam.
Currently in the theaters watching Dunda
2. It's inter law. Brilliant movie.
Well, I'm glad you got got to saw this
brilliant movie on your 20th birthday. I
wish you a very happy birthday. I wish
you a long and successful and prosperous
life. Do well. Do succeed in whatever
you whatever you're doing. All the best
and enjoy your birthday.
Kakashi says, "Are Sahil states
sovereign or Russian vasals?"
Most of them are dependent on Russia.
They used to be French vasals
and even now many of these Sahil nations
um
they their currency even now is
controlled by France.
Okay.
So from that perspective they can't be
sovereign. They are not economically
sovereign. The Sahel nations let's let's
take a look let's let's look into this
in a little more detail. Okay.
Sahel nations.
Sahel nations. Okay. What are the
nations? Key Sahelian nations. Seneagal.
Moitania. Maliaso. Nijair. Okay. Let's
say nijair. Nger currency.
It will be the ner. I'm sure this the
west African CF the Frank and that
currency. Okay. The west African CFA
Frank. It's issued by the Bank of
France. Okay.
It is issued by the Bank of Sefote
Africation.
It is issued by whom? It is issued
Central Bank of West African States.
Oh, really?
And
okay. So right now it is based out of da
da in synagal but some in some shape or
form or the other this is all controlled
by France. Okay obviously they'll try
and hide it as much as possible.
So historically the Sahel nations
whether it is Nijer it is Bokina it is
whoever else Sagal Mitania and so on so
forth they were all vasals of France
they were all colonized or occupied by
France and the French withdrew but they
they still kept these nations vasalized
and today some of these nations are
turning to Russia
for help.
So they will therefore in that case no
longer be vasalized by France. They may
be you could say semi- sovereign but
semi- sovereign with the assistance of
Russia. And if the Russian assistance is
no longer forthcoming they will again
get vasalized by somebody else. So these
are these are semi- sovereign semi-asal
states.
I would not consider them to be Russian
vasals but I would consider them to be
not completely but significantly
dependent on Russia. So obviously Russia
will also extract some benefit from it.
So not sovereign you could say semi-
vasalized states.
Anan Singh says seems the US is not as
powerful as you said. Is that so? So
I'll tell you what I'm I'm sure this
gives you great amount of joy that I
have turned out to be not entirely
correct. But the thing is this the world
is an evolving place. I have put out a
system
of rankings right hard power rankings.
And the last time I calculated that the
US had a hard hard power score of 94.
It is the it was the world's most
powerful nation from a hard power
perspective. What are the components of
the hard power
formula or recipe? You have things like
population area. You have things like uh
GDP. You have things like uh military
expenditure.
uh various aspects of sovereignty,
energy independence,
uh number of nukes and so many other
factors. All of these combined together
you can create a a score for each
nation. The US had a score of 94.
When I calculated this in 2024,
today
because of the US bungling
of its Iran campaign, if I recalculate
this, the hard power score of the US is
going to decline and Iran's hard power
score is going to rise. So the world
keeps changing. My dear friends, if I
said something two years ago, it may not
be applicable anymore and it should not
give you a great amount of pleasure. It
should make you think that why have
things changed?
Okay, I you know it it obviously pleases
you if somebody is proven to be wrong. I
have not been proven to be wrong. What I
said in 2024
was correct for 2024.
Today the Americans have the firepower
but they have messed up very badly with
their strategy, their tactics, their
assumptions and their execution and most
importantly their military doctrine.
So you may have the world's most
powerful military, but if you use it
incorrectly, you're going to still lose
and then your hard power score suffers.
So it is the US's own fault that it hard
its hard power score will now decrease
when I calculate it again. Anyway, I'm
I'm glad that this pleased you an Singh.
That's all right.
Black Panther says when the US is
fighting two wars Iran and Russia even
now China can't take Taiwan now then
what is best time
I think China should actually if I were
to put on put myself in Chinese shoes I
would wait for this war to go on for a
few months for a few more months and the
US to
to corner itself even more to dig an
even deeper hole for themselves
Because clearly Israel wants this war to
continue. And as long as Israel is
fighting, the Americans can't move out.
For some reason, the US has to be
involved wherever the US, wherever
Israel is involved.
So
if I was the Chinese leadership,
I would want this war to go on for a few
more months at least so that the
Americans
their their stockpiles of munitions and
whatnot, weapons, etc., etc., etc. are
depleted even further. But I would not
want to wait for let's say let's say 6
months to one year, maximum 6 months. By
that time the Americans may start
producing more munitions on an emergency
basis. So that process of restarting
production at at large scale that takes
typically a few months to begin maybe 6
months.
So I think the best time for China is 6
months from now,
four to 6 months from now. If the war is
still going at the time, 6 months from
now, that is the right time probably to
take Taiwan or depending on how long it
will take for the Americans to restart
large scale production of munitions,
missiles, etc. Whatever the time is,
whether it is 4 months, 6 months, or
even 8 months, maybe even 1 year,
whatever is the time it takes for them
to restart. wait that long and then make
a move on Taiwan. May that may be the
best time for China.
Pratipar Royce's favorite Dragon Ball Z
character. I've never watched Dragon
Ball Z. I don't know. I know some people
who have watched it. What is Goku or
something? Was it Goku? What's the
character called? Dragon Ball Z. I I
have never watched Dragon Ball Z.
Uh what's Dragon Ball Z? Let's see.
Dragon Ball Z.
What's that? Um, yeah, there's this
character called Goku, right?
Goku, Z warriors, etc. So, I have never
watched it. There are people whose
entire childhood was spent watching
this. I'm not one of those. Okay. Aloud
Kumar says, "Benefits and cons of
anxenex
in Northern
Mum."
What's Mum? Myanmar in short-term
long-term
benefits of annexing northern MM is
what? Myanmar.
Um, look, if you want to annex northern
Myanmar, you need to first of all plan
the operation very very thoroughly
benefits.
Benefits you can acquire the resources
of this region. You can reintegrate Kabo
Valley with Manipur and this area this
big area is full of lots tremendous
amounts of natural resources including
rare earth minerals. So that's a
benefit. Cons. What are the
shortcomings? What are the drawbacks?
All the tribes that really live in this
region are cookies and various Christian
converted tribes.
The people who lived in this region
historically were Hindus and Buddhists.
Today you have a bunch of wild cookies
and a whole bunch of tribes that have
been in the past 50 or 100 years
converted to Christianity. They they're
all aligned with the US. Some of them
are some of them are aligned with China.
They'll fight you.
If you enex them, they'll fight you
unless you know how to pacify them
thoroughly. Learn from the Americans. if
you want to learn how to pacify
somebody. But that that that's a messy
nasty process.
If they were culturally and
civilizationally aligned with us, then
the next session could have been done
peacefully. But these are all converted
to Abrahamic religions mainly
Christianity. So it's going to be mess.
Uh that's one drawback. Another drawback
is China will oppose you and they'll
fight you. So
Argabal says if China moves on Taiwan
while Russia escalates and the Iran
Israel conflict is Iran Israel US
conflict continues for two three months.
How would the US military handle
sustained multi-theater pressure? Why
Chinese tech is called cheap?
I would say Indians especially Indian
influencers and YouTubers and retired
mer mil military personnel these groups
of people in India they love to make fun
of Chinese technology.
India should be very careful to not get
overconfident about China.
The Chinese technology that is exported
to Pakistan may be trash.
The Chinese technology that is that Iran
is using right now, it's world class.
It's better than what the Americans
have. For example, the Iranians are
using Chinese BU
satellite positional techn satellite
positioning technology. The Americans
are unable to jam that
and it's more accurate allegedly than
the GPS that the Americans have.
Okay. The Chinese also have extremely
high quality satellite imaging
technology that gives Iran almost
realtime satellite images of of the
targets.
And the Chinese I believe their drones
are high quality, probably worldass,
maybe even better than Iranian drones.
Their missiles, we haven't seen them.
They also could be very high quality. We
should not take China lightly.
Indians love to make fun of China. You
know that may come back to bite you in
the backside.
Don't don't be overconfident about about
anybody. The Chinese have the world's
best industrial u capabilities
better than the US. Let's not take China
lightly. Uh now if China moves on
Taiwan, Russia escalates, Iran conflict
continues to three months, how would the
US military handle sustained
multi-theater pressure? They will
not be able to handle sustained
multi-theater pressure. When it comes to
an eastern theater, maybe China making a
move on Taiwan, the Americans will force
the Japanese and and the Koreans to
enter the war, South Koreans, which
means the Korean conflict resumes after
decades because North Korea will then
make a move on South Korea. That's
guaranteed. So the Korean war reerupts
and Japan is dragged into the conflict.
Okay.
And if that and and I think Russia will
sit it out, but they'll go on high alert
in the eastern zone. So the Americans
will
drag Japan and South Korea into the
conflict, which means Japan and South
Korea at some point in time get very
badly damaged or destroyed. The
Americans are fine with sacrificing
their vasals.
But even then, if the Chinese have
scaled up their production of drones and
missiles,
I wonder how long even that that lasts.
If the Chinese have sufficient
stockpiles, they'll be able to defeat
South Korea and Japan, both and the
Americans. If they have the numbers of
missiles and drones, it's just a
mathematical game at this point.
If you have more missiles and drones
than your opponent,
you win. It's just a numerical thing.
So the Americans won't be able to as
long as the Chinese are willing to take
damage to win. They'll win. The Chinese
thus far have been extremely risk
averse.
They're just buying time. They want to
produce as many drones and missiles as
possible in in whatever time is there
before the next war.
Right?
So I think China wins that and Indians
need to be very careful about Indians
need to stop making fun of China. China
is is not that bad. China is
technologically far ahead of India by
the way.
Our Rajun Rajar says why we made arrest
of the infiltrators public. Good
question. We could have kept it a secret
so that no one will ask them back.
That's a good question. Why did India
make this uh public? The arrest of the
American terrorist and the Ukrainian
mercenaries. Why did India make this
public? If we had kept this quiet,
then the Americans can't put pressure on
India in public. Can't ask for them
back. The Ukrainians can't make those
statements. So why did India make this a
public thing? India made this a public
thing
for some reason.
That's a reason. It's a India is sending
a message to Trump.
Clearly India is sending a message to
Trump and to the Americans. Now what is
the message and what are we looking for?
I don't know. Is there's this guy called
Nikil Gupta allegedly an Indian national
who was arrested by the Americans.
Right? He was made to confess that he
was involved in some kind of attempt to
kill an American terrorist Guratman
Singh Panun or something. So does India
want that guy back in exchange for this
American terrorist? Is that all we want
or is India actually
is India actually you know does India
really want to begin the process of
ending the manipur disaster.
So I don't know what the deal is but for
some reason we are sending a message to
Trump and to the Trump regime that
that's why this was made public. But
what is the long inner game? Maybe some
YouTube row agents will know about it. I
don't know about it.
Pratik Kumar Roy says do you believe in
God? Is there God? Well, I have never
seen any evidence of God. I have never
I have never witnessed or experienced
any supernatural activity.
Okay. So,
I am by training a scientist. I'm by tra
by by nature I'm a skeptical person. But
I'm also a very optimistic person. So, I
don't know. I have never seen any
observational evidence of God or any
supernatural element in this universe.
So I don't know from that perspective if
there's God or not. But I am very
hopeful. So you could say I'm a hopeful
agnostic. Agnostic in the sense that I
don't know if there's God or not. I I'm
not easy to convince. I don't blindly
believe things. So I but the universe is
so vast, so immense that I think this
the very scale and immensity of the
universe is so so huge that if you say
that I am an atheist, you're an idiot.
If you are, if you have some
intelligence, then you cannot be an
atheist.
The universe is being an atheist means
you're claiming I know everything that
there's in the universe and I know that
there's no God because I I I've seen
every inch of the universe myself. Only
an idiot will make such a claim from my
perspective. Maybe I'm the idiot for
thinking it for seeing it that way, but
whatever. So, the way I see it,
atheists,
okay, let's not talk about atheists. My
point is I am am an agnostic. I don't
know whether there is a god or whether
there isn't a god. But I'm hopeful that
there is a god. I'll be the happiest
person if god does indeed exist or gods
do indeed exist. I'll be the happiest
person. Right. Okay. V for valor says
thank you and to everybody watching this
also. Thank you.
Infernojes says, "One, do you have a
plan to leverage AI to solve answering
FAQs in your live streams? Two, despite
India's screw-ups, what soft signals
keep you hopeful?" Okay. Uh, do I have a
plan to leverage AI to help to solve
answering FAQs in my live streams? How
do I use AI to answer FAQs?
Um, I'm taking this these questions
live, right?
um how can I use AI in that? Uh when I
one way I could potentially use AI is
when I have uh even that's not actually
fair for the viewers but it's an idea.
So when I have these uh live streams in
which I take pre-selected questions,
live streams in which I select questions
that you have asked in the comments with
the hashtag askit in that case what I
could do if there's like 300 500
questions people have asked. I could
copy paste them all and dump into AI and
tell the AI to select the most
interesting 30 questions for me or
whatever. But even that's not a good
idea because then the AI will decide on
its own what is interesting, what's not.
it won't have my taste and my decision
making baked into it. Right?
So I don't see any way of using AI of
leveraging AI and uh yeah this ask a
show is entirely AI free entirely AI
free there's no
feasible reasonable way of integrating
AI into it
and even when it comes to selecting
questions it makes sense for me to go
through all the questions and manually
select what I feel are the most
important most interesting
questions and the questions that will
whose answers will give the most value
to my audience even that cannot be
handled by AI
right so there's no way of leveraging AI
as far as I can see
uh despite India's screw-ups what soft
signals keep me hopeful
what soft signals keep me hopeful
while India's huge potential keeps me
hopeful
mostly it's that it's India's huge
potential it's The potential of the
people, young people of India, it's it's
that that keeps me hopeful. The
potential is immense,
immense. And India has historically
produced highquality leaders. Not in the
past 100 years. The last highquality
leader we had was Subash Chandra Bos
like worldclass highquality leader.
And I apologize to those of you who are
offended by that because you had some
other leader in mind. But okay, the way
I see it, the last highquality
world-class leader we had was Subashra
Bose.
After that, we have not produced any
great leader.
Um but historically we have produced
like some of the greatest leaders the
humanity has ever seen. So that's
another thing that keeps me hopeful.
Yeah. And we have come a long way in the
since 1947. We have also gone backwards
in many ways since 1947. So it's a mixed
bag. But these are the things that keep
me hopeful.
Zir Kat says the current government
through its
excuse me what?
Okay. The current government through its
GE no etc. policies has effectively
killed more Hindus than orang
facilitating the erasure of Hindus.
Okay. Um
I don't know if statistically it is
correct or not.
Um Orurange it is New York Times said
that Orurange killed 5 million Hindus or
10 million Hindus which obviously is a
very conservative statement. If it's New
York Times, the actual number will be
maybe 10 10 times that or at least five
times that. Um,
so if orang let's say killed let's say
25,000 Hindus or 25 million Hindus
million million
have the those money been killed in
India the in the past let's say decade
I'm not sure about that. uh maybe those
money have may have been converted out
of Hinduism. I don't know about we don't
have the statistics for that also. So
I'm not really sure what the statistics
in data is but there definitely are
areas of concern for sure.
Sagi Kachara says not able to send super
chat. Why is that? Is the system not
allowing you to send it? Is the YouTube
system not allowing you to send? I'm
sorry to hear that sir. I'm very sorry
to hear that. That's beyond my control.
This is the platform right? the YouTube
platform. Um, sorry, I'm sorry to hear
that. I apologize.
Aditi Takar says, "Do you think Indra
Gandhi was better PM than Modi in terms
of geopolitics?"
Well,
she did, you know, give the Indian army
the go-ahhead to to bifurcate Pakistan
to to vivisect Pakistan.
Um, so that was a very decisive thing to
do.
uh it was also under her ages that India
tested the first nuclear weapon ever
but then
put the nuclear program in cold storage
right so that was perplexing why why
didn't India become a full-fledged
nuclear power after 1974
why not do like 20 30 more tests and
operationalize the nuclear deterrent why
not that was a huge huge uh lapse I
would say incomprehensible lapse. Uh she
did give the Indian army the go ahead
and cleared the path for them for our
great Indian army to destroy and defeat
Pakistan and break off East Pakistan and
converted to Bangladesh. Great.
Tremendous. But then we sign she signed
the similar agreement. Similar agreement
giving back in the territory we had
captured Hajibir pass and so on. That
again is perplexing. It's like
a couple of steps back.
So she did uh play the game right with
the USSR against the Americans. So many
good steps but also many missteps
about the current prime minister. I
think I will make a public assessment
only after there is a next prime
minister a few years down the line. Too
early to make pass judgment when the he
is still prime minister. Right.
Right.
Panjal Chasia says CIA agent Scott in
Manipur. Is the government waking up?
We'll see about that. I discussed this
in on mult multiple occasions in this
liveream. So I'm sure you must have seen
that. Uh so I've answered the question.
I hope the government is waking up. I
hope so.
Risha Pawar says ob importance of
objective of war and its impact on war
psychology. For example, operation
sindur which happens only four days.
Besides we were on the stronger side
that US lacks.
that US lacks. What does the US lack?
Okay, now I don't know what is US
lacking. I'm not sure what you're asking
there, but importance of the objectives
of war and its impact on war psychology.
So
what is important
when you are about to go to war is
having crystal clear is to have a
crystal clear understanding of what your
objectives are.
Understand this.
War is a continuation of politics by
other means.
War is the continuation of politics by
military means which means that the
objectives have to be political.
Politics is not the continuation of war
by other means.
So you don't go into war and then let
the military outcomes determine what
your objectives are. No, before you go
into war, your leadership, your
political leadership needs to very
clearly define
what constitutes victory,
what needs to happen so that we can
declare victory. Right?
So, it's very clear to know exactly what
your objectives are, your political and
military objectives.
That way the armed forces know exactly
what they're supposed to accomplish in
what in what time. Also when that
clarity is there, you can go into war
with full force. If your clarity if your
objectives aren't clear, your military
actions are going to be muddled and
confused.
Right? So that's why the objectives have
to be very clear, crystal clear.
Operation Sundur happened only 4 days.
we on stronger side and so on. Yeah. I
don't know. I'm not sure what US is
lacking but okay.
Okay. Old tank says is it possible that
IRGC is compromised with MOSAD and CIA
as GCC oil and gas destruction is
benefiting US? No. No. GCC oil and gas
destruction is happening every time it's
happening in response to attacks on
Iranian oil and gas infrastructure. Only
when there's an attack by Israel or the
US on Iranian infrastructure is Iran
launching an attack on a GCC nation's
oil and gas infrastructure. It's
happening only in response to that. And
if the Iranians if the Israelis or
Americans launch attacks on Iranian
infrastructure and Iran doesn't respond
then Iran is losing it loses
credibility. It loses the advantage. It
it starts falling back in the war. So
Iran is doing whatever it's doing in
response. It's not compromised by MOSAD
or CIA. Absolutely not. That's that much
is clear by now. Maybe there were Mossad
or CIA assets in the IRGC maybe in 2025.
I don't think there's anyone left today.
Okay.
Anoj says, "Don't you think Iran can
also be a security threat in the future
if for any reason our relations get bad?
India's Shia Muslims seem to blindly
follow
Iran's religious leaders, they can
create unrest.
Look, I'll not go into religious
matters. Okay? And u historically Iran
has never
caused any actual problems for India.
Iran has historically historically means
19 since 1975. You geniuses, some genius
is going to come and say, "No, but in
1965 this happened. In 1965, Iran was
ruled by an American puppet." I'm
talking about post 1979.
You will drag out Nadisha also who was a
Turk not Persian. So those geniuses
please go and talk to somebody else not
to me. But since 1979
Iran's government has not taken any
action that is detrimental to Indian
interests. Their leaders have from time
to time made statements that annoy
India. Sure. But they have never taken
any action that is against India's
interests. That's one thing. As long as
India and Iran don't have a common
border, relations won't get bad. When
you have two big nations with a common
border, that's where you have tensions.
Right? I don't see Iran being a security
threat to India in the future. I don't
see it happening anytime in the in the
foreseeable future.
Ranjan Singh Raat says, "Is your course
in on geopolitics and history
available?" Well, the last time I
checked it was, is there any problem? If
there is a problem, please let me know.
I'll look into it.
Sagnik Acharia says, "Seems only way to
is to rectify this chaotic democratic
system at the core, but the inevitable
outcome of that is sanctions and
isolation. War maybe." You see, in order
to rise,
you have to first go through a period of
pain.
It is clear that this chaotic democratic
system is ai system where you have an
elite class of people whose interests
aren't aligned with the most of whom
have interests that aren't in line with
India's national and civilizational
interests and these people are rent
seekers who will never allow society to
progress the way it should so progress
who will never allow the full energy and
potential of India's people and youth to
unleashed.
The system is a parasitical rent seeking
system.
This so-called democratic system, that's
what it is. If you dismantle it, there's
going to be a period of chaos,
maybe sanctions, maybe isolation, even
war.
The alternative is you never transcend
this system. You know, war, chaos, it's
not always a bad thing. It often leads
to the rejuvenation of a nation after a
period of pain.
So I'm not saying I want war. I'm not
saying saying I want chaos. But we
certainly need to transcend this system
and replace it with a better system.
Otherwise this country will never
achieve its potential. You have to also
understand that. So what's the way out
is the question.
Skeptical potato says in the TV show The
Expanse, a terrorist group redirects
asteroids to impact cities on Earth, a
stealth coating was used to make the
asteroids invisible to telescopes. Is
this possible in the near future? It's
not possible in the near future, but it
is
it could be possible in the distant
future.
Uh this entire scenario is perfectly in
line with the laws of physics. So there
is nothing in the laws of physics that
that go that prevents this from
happening. Right? This is allowed as per
the laws of physics.
So you can have spacecraft that can go
and drag satellites after out of their
current orbit around the sun and
redirect them towards the earth's orbit.
You can certainly have some kind of
coating that makes asteroids almost
impossible or de facto invisible to
telescopes
so that you don't see them approaching.
Maybe you coat them with with a thin
layer of carbon, black carbon which
makes them almost impossible against the
darkness of the sky
so that you cannot see them until they
are right right in front right upon you.
It's definitely possible but it's not
possible in the near future. It may be
possible in the next maybe 200 years,
maybe 100 years, not possible in the
near future. Impossible.
Market whisperer says, "Why are Indians
reactive and not proactive? It's the
norm, not the exception." Which means
it's part of our culture. How can we
fundamentally change this? See, the the
past 1,000 years, we were under foreign
occupation and we developed various
various uh behavioral patterns to help
us survive.
Okay.
For a long time we resisted and fought
but especially after 1857 when we were
to when our war of independence was
completely and brutally crushed.
That's when the the the the British
re-engineered reconfigured our society
created an elite class that was a class
of collaborators with them and for the
rest of society we just had to somehow
survive.
So lots of Indians became fatalist,
fatalistic, passive, reactive, leave it
to the gods. We'll just continue to
exist and all that. So when a nation is
under foreign occupation for a very very
very long time, this is what happens,
right? How do we fundamentally change
this? By Yeah, that's a good question.
Uh we have to change our system of
governance. We have to probably go to
war a few times and win a few times. uh
we have to change our education system.
A lot of things have to be changed.
Right now also the Indian society is
very very passive in in in in in the
face of foreign infiltration. Oh, our
government should take care of it. Our
society is very passive in in face in
the face of uh rent seeking, alleged
corruption so on so forth. We have
become very passive, right? We are
fundamentally a very orderly society,
very civilized society and sometimes you
can become too civilized. So that's kind
of what it is. So many changes need to
happen for us to transcend this this
particular
uh set of characteristics we have
acquired.
Vikram says is if Christianity is
declining in the west why are they not
trying to revive it there and rather
trying to gain grounds in new countries.
A Christianity it gains ground in its
specific circumstances.
Um
see in the west what's happened is that
the west is very educated. The western
countries everyone's educated. Everyone
can see that Christianity whatever it
claims is not true. It claims to be a
religion of love.
It claim claims to be a religion of
whatever miracles and all. And everyone
can see that it's not what it is. Right?
Their priests their priests have been
exposed doing all kinds of horrific
Epstein- like things all across the
world. The west has seen through that.
But in a country like India, you can't
speak about that otherwise things
happen, you know. So in places like
India and in third world countries there
is still a lot of fertile ground for the
spread of Christianity. So in the west
they are doomed. They are finished in
the west.
That's why they want to stay relevant by
by now using third world countries as
the hosts for their religion.
Minimalist Maverick says India used to
give money to Russia for Russia to send
weapons to Afghanistan since 2014 status
on that. I have no idea. No idea about
that. Why is India not giving any
support to Afghanistan against Pakistan?
Very disappointing. What do you want
India to do? Get involved in the war?
No. Afghanistan is doing a tremendous
job of fighting against Pakistan.
They're doing a terrorist terrific job
against the Pakistani terrorist regime.
India will not give any overt support to
Afghanistan.
Whatever support India will give will
not be
communicated to you and me and the
world. It will be done quietly.
Okay?
I'm pretty sure we are uh offering moral
support or something or the other
quietly to Afghanistan.
So let's not be disappointed.
Vikram, thank you very much. Vikram,
thank you.
Pratip Kumar Roy says in a recent video,
Khanser
Khanser told that this is the best time
for Pakistan occupied Kashmir, US,
Iran, Pakistan because every everyone is
busy.
Cancer is cancer crazy or what? We have
lost our Navic. Navic capabilities. NAV
vic. Navic. What is Navik? Come on
cancer.
N A V IC.
Navic satellite system. The Indian
regional navigation satellite system
IRNSS.
Let's say India goes to war against
Pakistan to take back P. The Americans
what is the first thing they will do?
they will switch off GPS for the Indian
military. So we had a backup for that.
We had the IRNSS or Navic system but the
government of India a bunch of geniuses
they have allowed this system to become
defunct. So now the Navic system is no
longer proper properly operational and
if the GPS is switched off our missiles
will no longer get satellite positioning
inputs. So they will not be able to
strike the targets accurately.
The Indian military also will not have
GPS so they won't know exactly where
they are.
This is the genius level achievement of
the government of India today. Do you
think this is the right time to take
back P? Has Khanser not thought about
this seriously?
Okay. Eublic of India says Scott Bessent
said the said the US may lift sanctions
on Iranian oil stuck in tankers. Isn't
easing sanctions during a war
contradictory to its strategy?
Scott Besson said the US may lift
sanctions on Iranian oil struck stuck in
tankers.
Okay, I'm not aware of this. U
I'll have to look into it.
Lifting sanctions on Iranian oil stuck
in tankers.
Okay. So I I'm not I am not aware of
this. I don't have information about
this. So I will
easing sanctions against Iran is
obviously contradictory to the strategy.
easing sanctions, lifting sanctions on
specific tankers or whatever may be a
different thing. So, we'll see.
Ghoulibar says, "Sad to see a cookie
synthesizer
in one of your podcast spreading lies
talking about someone from JNU. Big fan
of yours though.
You know, I've done more than a 100
podcasts, right? And I have done all my
podcasts in good faith.
And after
hosting more than 100 podcasts,
I have learned some lessons.
Some of those people, a few of those
people who I invited,
I regret inviting. A very small number
of people I regret inviting.
One of those people
became a member of parliament and I
regret inviting that one person.
Yeah. I had no idea that person would uh
go and become a member of so and so
political party and so on.
Yeah.
So yeah, there are some people who in
retrospect
with the benefit of hindsight I should
not have invited but at the time I did
it in good faith and I had no idea what
what actions the person would take in
the future. Yes.
So we all make mistakes and we we learn
from those mistakes. Yeah.
Ritvikuanchi says 20,000 and the six
captured foreign individuals
went to train these cookies from Indian
land that means we are compromised.
Somebody took the money and let them go.
Same allegations about BSF taking money
to let kungos in. What can I say sir?
What can I say?
these these allegations about BSF.
You can look up the news archives and
there are multiple instances,
multiple reports in the news of BSF
personnel being arrested
for taking uh money to allow
Bangladeshes to cross into India. Let's
let's see if I can find something. So,
it's not me making claims, it's it's the
news.
BSF personnel arrested
bribes
that's bribe right
graft charge Kerala
graft charge once again
BSF commandant arrested for receiving
bribes from cross borders to smugglers
there are so many stories like this news
reports like this have come out right
M
crossber border bribes.
Yeah, there are so many so many so many
such stories.
I mean ask yourselves this one question.
Who is in charge of making sure
Bangladeshes don't cross over into
India? It's the BSF. We also know there
are tens of millions of Bangladeshes in
India.
How did they come into India? How did
they how did they cross over into India?
Yeah.
So there are clear it's there's no
question that there are huge problems
and lots of allegedly compromised people
when it comes to various
branches
and institutions
in India.
Yeah.
Now when it comes the Misaram CM, the
chief minister of Misaram last year he
said a year ago he said
that US and UK personnel were crossing
over into Myanmar from Misoram and India
and training insurgents which means
terrorists and so on and he was talking
to about he was talking about a case
from 2024.
So this has been an ongoing process of
Americans and British personnel
training cookie terrorists in Myanmar
supplying them with drones that are then
used on Indian citizens in Manipur also
against Burma possibly. Why has India
been allowing this? What kind of stupid
absurd geopolitical game is the
government of India perhaps involved in?
Or maybe the government of India is not
involved in it.
But are they not aware of this
right? What is happening? Is this not a
monumental failure? Seriously, I just
don't get it.
Ritikui says, "Do we have alternative to
LPG for the cooking cooking gas?" Uh
well there is a substance a chemical
substance called dimethile ether dme
that seems to be an excellent
alternative to uh cooking gas and it can
be produced without having uh hydrocarb
without having petroleum or whatever. So
you can produce it in India I suppose in
large quantities. So it's a good
alternative but we have to produce it at
scale for it to be a proper replacement
for LPG.
I'm sure it can be done
uh on a war footing if required. So I
think the government of India should
should go for it.
Market whispers with every country going
bullish on drones we should also
concentrate on cheap and effective anti-
drone technology. That might be the
differentiator. No. Yes. Yes. Yes. Yes.
Every see drones are not difficult to
manufacture.
They they are not very high techch
equipment
and they are pretty cheap to
manufacture.
Pretty cheap,
right? Which means that even a non-h
high-tech country can produce can mass
produce drones at scale without
spending, you know, tremendous amounts
of money. Which means that if you are at
the receiving end of maybe waves of
drones
then you will have to to to
produce
effective and cheap anti- drone
measures counter measures at scale
and that obviously will be the
differentiator. So what we can do is we
can look into what the Ukrainians have
done in terms of drone anti- drone
counter measures.
They have come up with anti- drone
solutions that are cheaper than the
drones that are coming in
and now they are going to be sharing
that with the Americans to potentially
uh counter the Iranian shahed drones. So
India so the Ukrainians have developed
these this technology these these
counter measures over the past uh four
years or so that they have been involved
in this war with Russia. So India needs
to instead of trying to reinvent the
wheel just look into what the Ukrainians
have been doing. There are reports about
their their counter measures in the
media and so on just look at that study
that and instead of trying to reinvent
the wheel start off from what the
Ukrainians have been doing and take it
from there. So yes, I agree with you. We
need to concentrate on cheap and
effective counter drone technology at
scale.
Messi aim me aim says Messi aim what
indicators would signal that this war is
transitioning from a contained regional
issue into a global war with direct
involvement from other nations. What
indicators the the involvement of other
nations in the war are is an indicator.
So if more nations get involved, let's
say Azarbaijan gets dragged into the
war, right? Let's say um Pakistan gets
involved in some way in the war. Maybe
the Americans rope in some European
nations and then the Iranians take some
action against them. Let's say the the
Ukrainians
get involved in some way. They are let's
say the Ukrainians start providing the
Americans with anti- drone counter
measures and then Iran says that's
enough and they launch a missile strike
at Kiev for example they can
then then Ukraine gets directly involved
maybe maybe the Israelis you know launch
some very heavy strikes on Iran using
some
fancy weapons and then Russia and China
get involved. So these are signals that
that tell you that this is escalating
from a regional contain contained
regional issue into a more global war.
The indicators are more countries
joining the fry.
Mihir says what do you think of Anduril
YQF44A
Roadrunner etc. Also do you think India
should join FCAS or GCAP with Hall
H out of AMCA production? Uh so many
acronyms you've thrown at me here. Um,
okay. What is YQF44A?
Let's see.
YQF-44A.
Okay. So, that's a unmanned combat.
Okay. Thing. Right. Right. Right. Right.
Right. Looks very futuristic and scary
and obviously looks very expensive.
So, it's a UCAV, right? Unmanned combat
aerial vehicle.
So, I'm sure the technology is some of
the best in the world, but if it's an
American product, it's going to be
extremely expensive to produce.
Um, but it's obviously a good
alternative to having a human being on
on a fighter plane. So, Anduril is
obviously this company that produces
these weapon systems and so on, right? I
think it's a very high-tech company
which and its objective is to is to make
big profits, right? And profit from war.
So it's part of the American military
industrial complex. It's one of the
newer members of the American military
industrial complex and yeah
uh road runner I'm not sure what it is.
What is FCAS or GCAP? Let's see.
FCAS
what is FCAS?
Future combat European combat system. I
think India should stay out of all
foreign
ventures. What's GCAP? GCAP
global once again it's a foreign thing
India should stay out of these
multinational things and all India
should develop its own technologies okay
I should India should stay out of FCAS
or GCAP or whatever the hell it is India
should develop its own technologies
in enough of India depending on others
okay even if these are multilateral
multinational things where every nation
will share some of the technology
Absolutely not. Stay out of it. Develop
our own technology is what we need to
do. Anishh Barha, hydration reminder.
Thank you so much. Thank you for the
reminder. Let me have some more
hydration.
Thank you. I needed that. Thank you so
much.
Zir Kamat says Isra
is
themselves probably want US presence
reduced
eliminated in the region. I think
there's a backdoor agreement between
them and Iran. Well, that is a
speculation.
Obviously,
nothing is impossible
and we'll see about that if that's the
case. I I don't know. I don't know.
Re e public of India says at this point
Trump's objective seems crystal clear.
Taco
Trump's objective is a taco. What is
taco? Trump always chickens out. That's
taco.
But Iran is in no mood to give them a
face saving exit. What's my view? Oh
yeah, absolutely. Trump wants to exit
this war. It's gone very poorly for the
United States.
There are two issues with this with
wanting to exit. Number one, they can't
exit while Israel is still fighting.
Somehow the Americans,
they have to serve Israel. That that's
become amply clear by now that the
United States does whatever the Israelis
want them to do.
It's almost like the US is an Israeli
vasal.
So as long as Israel is fighting and
escalating, the US can't exit the war.
Secondly, Trump is trying through
backdoor channels and all trying to open
a negotiating thing with the with the
Iranians and negotiate some kind of face
saving exit and Iranian saying nothing
doing. We are not interested in a
negotiated exit unless you accept our
terms, our humiliating terms and those
terms the Americans can't accept. Number
one,
shut down all military bases in the
region permanently. Number two, pass a
law in Congress that permanently
prevents the United States or any future
president from waging a war against
Iran. Number three, pay huge reparations
for damages to Iran and so on. The US
can never accept those those terms. So
Trump wants a face- saving exit. Iran
doesn't want to give him that. That
tells you Iran is confident they're
going to prevail in this war. Imagine
that. Imagine that.
Abishek says, "Can International
Committee force the US to stop war?" No.
There's no nobody can force the US to do
anything. International international
committees can request the US to stop
the war. They can exhort the US
strongly recommend to the US to stop the
war. They can't force the US to stop the
war. No one is powerful enough to do
that.
Sai Krishna says, "Hypothetically, if
the US nukes Iran,
can the radiation spread to the Gulf
radiating cloud? Does Iran have dirty
bomb?"
If somebody nukes Iran,
then the radiation when a nuclear
explosion occurs,
there's a huge release of radiation,
radioactive particles into the
atmosphere.
And it that the that radioactive cloud
of radiation and particles rises high
into the atmosphere. There's a burst of
gamma rays and all that's the initial
thing and all but eventually there's the
radioactive um um
fallout of the explosion. the particles
that rise high into the atmosphere
like kilometers into the atmosphere,
tens of kilometers into atmosphere and
then the cloud disperses and spreads and
and travels around the world with the
air currents.
So this cannot be contained in one
country. It may very well reach Israel
and and fall in in along with
precipitation and rain in Israel. It
could move eastwards and come into
Pakistan
into the Gulf region south. It will go
anywhere. Eventually it will reach the
whole world in some shape or form and
for a few months rainfall will be
dangerous.
Right? So in 1986 when there was uh the
Chernobyl event uh the Chernobyl reactor
was breached and a cloud of radioactive
material was unleashed was released from
Chernobyl.
This cloud spread across Europe. Now I
was a kid living in Europe at the time
and for a few months we kids were
prohibited from playing football on the
grass or running on the grass because
precipitation, rainfall, snowfall,
whatever would bring radioactive
particles with it and the grass surface
would be irradiated to some extent. So
that sort of thing will
like be even more relevant when if if
there is a nuclear explosion, the
detonation of a nuclear device. So that
can't be contained in one country. It'll
spread out. That's bad. Does Iran have
dirty bomb? I don't know. But they have
file material. They have at least 60%
enriched uranium. Lots of it. Maybe
hundreds of kilos of that. And they may
also have sufficient maybe a few kilos
of 90 plus%
highly enriched uranium which could be
enough
to produce a handful of proper non-
dirty nuclear warheads but they
definitely have more than enough nuclear
file material for lots of dirty bombs.
Mata says hello from Brazil. Hello good
to have you. Why aren't we cooperating
more? Areas of possible cooperation and
trade and business, agro business,
satellite technology, it renewables and
biouels etc. We should cooperate more.
We are developing nations.
Brazil is this very large nation, the
largest nation in the Americas in in
South America with tremendous natural
resources and tremendous potential for
growth. Brazil, India, we are both
members of bricks. We are both global
south nations. We are both nations who
don't seek to have war with other
countries. There's a tremendous amount
of potential for mutual cooperation
between India and Brazil. I would say we
should also cooperate in aviation
technology. Brazil has this fantastic
company called Embrier that produces
high quality aircraft. Why can't India
manufacture some of these aircraft that
it needs under license from Embreer?
Right.
Uh renewables absolutely biouels, it
absolutely satellite technology yes we
have ISRO we could launch your
satellites for you we could jointly uh
co-develop satellites co-produce
satellites cooperate in space
exploration and technology agri business
absolutely trade
this this the potential
is unlimited right I I'm not sure why we
are not cooperating more I I would love
to have Brazilians come to India for
tourism. I would love to have Indians go
to Brazil for tourism. Not just Rio the
Janeiro, Sao Paulo. What about Manawus?
What about other parts of Brazil? Brazil
has such wonderful
uh tourism potential. Indians should tap
into that. So I think there's tremendous
amount of potential. I'm not sure why we
aren't cooperating more. I think uh the
two governments need to get their act
together and interface better and uh
create more avenues for people-to-people
cooperation, businessto business
cooperation and so much more. One issue
is that we are so far apart from each
other. We are on opposite sides of the
planet. That could be one of the issues
because both the populations aren't
exactly very rich populations, very
wealthy populations. Um Brazil's per
capita GDP is higher than that of India.
India's is lower. So both are uh you
could say low lower income nations and
that could be one of the reasons but I'm
sure that the two governments can work
together and facilitate more cooperation
needs to happen. Yes. So Matias so thank
you so much for your comment. It's great
to have you as a viewer and I wish you
the best and I look forward to there
being much more cooperation between our
two nations. Thank you. Have a nice day.
Hitesh says India is managing a lot of
strategic autonomy right now. Till when
can we keep this up? Won't there be a
point where this approach stops working
in our favor?
India is managing a lot of strategic
autonomy right now. How long can we keep
this up
and uh will this approach stop working
at some point of time in our favor?
You can have strategic autonomy as long
as you have leverage
over other nations.
What kind of leverage? Well,
you can you have a great big population.
Other nations want to trade with you.
That's leverage. Let's say you
manufacture wonderful things that the
world needs. That's leverage. Let's say
you export highquality services the
you have a very powerful and scary
military. That's leverage. Let's say you
have
nuclear weapons. That's leverage. So, as
long as you have leverage and that
leverage keeps increasing,
that's as long as that happens, this
approach can keep working in your favor.
But if some more powerful nation decides
that your leverage isn't worthwhile now
and they don't want to um
cooperate anymore and they decide and
they clearly know they have way more
leverage than you then that stops
working.
So it depends on various factors.
Okay.
Right. Uh Roshan Raja says amused by
your knowledge in physics. Quite a
podcast
I came through today. Thank you for
expanding my thoughts beyond my ability.
Well, you're very welcome. Which podcast
are you referring to? I've done lots of
them. But anyway, I'm glad that uh it
was useful for you. Thank you. Okay.
Nodit WMA says, "Why haven't Gulf
nations thought of a rail corridor
bypassing Hormos? Can start from Kuwait,
Saudi Arabia, UAE, Oman, sidings from
Bahrain and Qatar. I'm not sure why they
haven't thought of it.
Maybe the US had some kind of role to
play in this. Maybe they would have have
Let's see. Have they always ever thought
of a rail corridor?
Have the Gulf nations ever thought of a
rail corridor bypassing Hormuz?
Not sure if they have.
They have planned etc etc. GCC. Okay.
Okay. Okay. proposed, proposed,
proposed, proposed.
So why has this never been done? I mean,
they're still planning and proposing it.
I'm not sure. Maybe they were
complacent. Maybe they were advised that
it's not necessary. Who advised them? I
wonder who did. I don't know. It's a
good idea, right? The thing is even if
you have a rail corridor bypassing
hormones, you can't carry petroleum on
railways, right? You need to have
pipelines. What they would have needed
is actually what would have been useful
would be pipelines bypassing hormos.
Ideally underground pipelines
overground pipelines can also be
targeted by missiles and drones.
But thing is even if you have
underground pipelines and if you have a
high quality uh missile with a with a
penetrating warhead, it can destroy
underground pipelines too. The problem
is all of this is too exposed and too
vulnerable. Even if they have a railway,
the railway line can be destroyed in
multiple locations,
right? And if you have cheap drones, you
can keep on destroying the railway line.
Even if it's if you if the Gulf nations
keep on repairing it. And how long is
that sustainable? If you have a
pipeline, the pipeline can be blasted in
multiple points, then what happens?
Even if you have an underground pipeline
that can be destroyed with penetrating
warheads. So you see,
even if you do all these things, you
still can't bypass hormones.
If your adversary is determined
to block you to block your oil
transiting this region, what happened?
Okay.
Right. Goullibar says, "Tell clearly is
Israel an enemy or 60% convergence, 40%
anti-India.
Give a detail in neutral perspective or
is this subject topic interestbased
friendly an enemy as well?
Look, Israel is a nation with its own
interests
and those interests aren't 100% aligned
with India's interests which is
obviously natural. No two nations have
interests that completely align.
Okay.
Um
now is this subject topic interest based
friendly and enemy as well?
I don't know what that means. My point
is Israel isn't necessarily an enemy of
India but Israel has its own interests
which in many instances
don't align with India's interests.
Okay. And of course as such it will
pursue its own interests
and India will pursue its own interests
and wherever the interests converge and
align we will work together. On other
things we will not work together. For
example, let me give you the example of
Armenia.
India and Iran have been working
together to support Armenia.
Israel has been working to support
Azarbaijan, Armenia's mortal enemy.
So, India and Israel are on opposite
sides of a conflict in the Caucasus
region. You see that? That's an example
of where India and Israel our interests
are they don't align. They oppose each
other. So India is providing weapons and
radars to Armenia
that can be used in a war future war
against Azarbaijan which is Israel's
ally.
It can destroy Azarbaijan's potentially
destroy Azarba Aarba's oil
infrastructure which would be a problem
for Israel. So you see there are such
things that we have in the world. It's
it's a complex world. Okay, Big Smoke
Gaming says, "We cut Russian oil under
pressure. We lost our discount then paid
a premium to buy it back. Are we
sacrificing the long-standing
Indorussian relationship?" We aren't
sacrificing it. We are under pressure by
the Americans. And we have
multiple times in the past buckled under
American pressure.
We were buying oil from Venezuela in the
2000s.
When the Americans told India, stop
buying Venezuelan oil. We said, "Okay,
sir, we'll stop." We buckled under
pressure. We were buying oil from Iran,
our neighbor. And the Americans said,
"Stop buying Russ Iranian oil." We said,
"Okay, sir." And we stopped completely
buying Iranian oil.
Right now, we were buying Russian oil.
Trump comes and says, "You will stop
buying Russian oil." So, we reduced our
purchase of Russian oil. We did not stop
buying Russian oil. We reduced our
purchases of Russian oil under American
pressure. Now when there's a problem, we
have gone back to Russia and we buying
more oil. So clearly see it doesn't tell
the world that India is unreliable. It
tells the world India is weak.
And weak nations are by nature
unreliable. Not because we have a
character defect but because we are
weak. Right?
So India seems to be believe that
American interests are very important
for us and uh India seems to believe
that we really need America America's
cooperation in various things for us to
survive and that may be true. Maybe
America has that much leverage over us
in a variety of ways. Right?
You will not see Russia forcing India to
sacrifice our relationship with America.
But America always does this with the
other countries. So this tells the world
that India is a weak nation not strong
enough to stand on its own like Iran or
Russia or China. India doesn't belong in
the same league as these these nations
and clearly India does not. Pushha is a
new member. Thank you very much. Welcome
to the channel's membership sir. Anumita
Roy Chadri says thank you so much for
your dedicated detailed and unbiased
take on geopolitics. Thank you very
much. You are very welcome indeed. I
really appreciate uh your message of
support. Thank you very much.
Gulibar says F-35 hit and damaged Czech
news or panilo. You look sad today.
Where you crying crying? I look sad
today. I'm not sad. I'm good. But
anyway, thank you for the reminder to
drink water. They must bring more water.
Now, let's check the news. What
happened? F35.
Let's see what happened. USF35 struck by
Iranian fire. Makes emergency landing.
IRGC releases video.
Suspected Iranian fire. Possible Iranian
strike
taking fire over Iran.
So, isn't this a stealth aircraft that
is invisible to radar? How did it take
Iran and fire the fantastic F-35? What
happened? Where is Trump today? He for
the for months he was taunting India
claiming that India had lost four
fighter planes then five fighter planes
then six fighter planes then seven
fighter planes. He was having a jolly
good time taunting India with these wild
claims. Where is he today? How many
aircraft has the US lost in this war?
Anyway, thank you for bringing yeah for
notifying me of this news.
Pratik Shenoi says Israel wanted to
destroy Pakistan nuclear weapon program
even had asked India for help in the
1980s
and Pakistan openly hates Israel but you
said they are friends when
why did they go from being enemies to
friends listen I've explained this in
great detail that there is no open
evidence of this
there's no open evidence of this you
have to follow a certain chain of logic
let me repeat the chain of logic to
I think what you want is a document that
officially announces that Pakistan and
Israel are friends and allies officially
signed by the prime minister of Pakistan
and Israel only then you will say that
okay you are right
you have to understand subtle clues too
right
Pakistan is a US basal it's a US dog
slave puppet
and America
it seems it's an Israeli asset
And it gives Israel unconditional
support.
So then the question is what is the
relationship between Israel and
Pakistan?
Pakistan says Pakistan says that it
hates Israel. Israel in the 80s
1980s wanted to destroy Pakistan's
nuclear program. That is like last
century. Today what's the deal?
When the Pakistani dictator comes to
Washington DC,
there is an event arranged by the
Pakistan embassy or considered for him
in his honor and there's a Israeli
military presence there. How is it
possible? Tell me. This was reported in
in the media, right?
When Pakistan launches an air strike
three days ago on Afghanistan and on a
hotel in on a on a hospital in Kabul
killing 400 people,
an Israeli account with 1 million
followers on Twitter comes to Pakistan's
aid and says this was not a hospital, it
was a Taliban arms and ammunition depot.
Why is Israel supporting Pakistan in
this in terrorism?
Right?
Do you see that there's multiple clues
that that point in that direction?
Do you see that, sir? Right. You have to
look in look at these subtle clues. In
geopolitics, you will not see everything
in black and white.
Two nations, if they are cooperating,
they will not issue a certificate. We
are now officially cooperating. They'll
keep it under wraps as far as possible.
Pakistan is supposed to be the policeman
in Gaza under Trump,
right? The Trump peace board or whatever
board of peace
Pakistan is going to send soldiers
there, right? Board of peace. Who who is
going to be helped by that? Is it Trump
who's going to be helped by that or is
it Israel who's going to be helped by
that? Look at all the data points. Learn
how to analyze things. Learn how to
understand subtle clues
and see in what direction the clues
consistently point. Please learn these
things. It'll help.
Deep learner says, "Wasn't there a Hamas
link that came out in the Bahalgam
attack?" In that case, there seems to be
an Iranian involvement in terrorism in
India. Hamas operates independently of
Iran.
Okay.
Now,
there was no Hamas link in the Pulgum
attack. What happened is there was some
kind of meeting of terrorists in
Pakistan
occupied Kashmir and some Hamas
terrorist or leader or something was
present there.
So that was the extent of the
involvement of Hamas. Hamas is clearly
anti-India.
They have common cause with the
Pakistanis.
See Hamas
is a is a bunch of Sunni Muslims, right?
It's a Sunni Muslim terrorist
organization and Pakistan is a Sun Sunni
Muslim nation. Israel is a Shia nation
but they support Hamas because Hamas is
anti-Israel and Iran is also
anti-Israel. So that is the kind of
connection there is. It's not an
ideological or religious connection.
It's a it's my enemy's enemy is my
friend that sort of thing. Iran does not
fund or finance Hamas as far as I know.
The funding and financing goes to the
Ansarah faction in Yemen that is the
Houthis and to various Shia elements in
the region
not to Hamasbah
yes not to Hamas so if Hamas has some
involvement with Pakistani terrorism it
doesn't mean Iran is involved
Namit Mahara hello hello indeed hello
good to have you Namit other says Donald
Trump admits Iran's high IQ in the war
and says they are powerful in his latest
press statement. His tone seems to be
changing dramatically. Is the US losing
its edge in the war? Isn't it obvious
the past 20 days or so? The US is is is
failing. It has failed thus far to
achieve any of its objectives. It has
been shocked and stunned by Iran's
resistance. Iran obviously has taken
tremendous damage.
It's losing god knows how many thousands
of people, but it's fighting. And the
Americans and Israelis together, their
combined efforts
are unable to defeat Iran. It's stunning
for sure. And Trump has been claiming
every single day that Iran has already
been defeated. They have already lost.
They have already lost, but they still
have a nuclear program. They have
already lost, but they've closed the
state of Hormos. They have already lost.
We already won but they are still around
fighting what? So his obviously his ch
his his tone will change right?
Obviously
the US is it losing its edge in the war?
It's been losing its edge in the war
since day one.
Vir Kumar says the past few days have
exposed o over dependence on LPG gas. Is
this an opportunity to completely
revolutionize the space? Are there
already technologies that can support
this? one there's one alternative called
uh dimethile ether if it can be produced
by India in at scale in large quantities
it can uh replace that so let's see once
again
dimethile ether production process
how do you pro how do you produce this
uh indirect synthesis methanol
dehydration and direct synthesis from
sin gas the indirect process which is
most common involves producing methanol
methanol from natural gas or biomass
mass which is then degraded to create
DME. Okay. So from biomass. How about
that? From
from biomass. How do you do it from
biomass?
So you convert biomass into sing gas CO
plus H2 via gasification and so on. uh
so India produces tremendous amounts of
biomass which is essentially you know
organic waste of various kinds so I
suppose you can produce DME at scale
from that
of course we have to create a whole
process and system for that but it's
possible so it's this is so India
definitely can treat this challenge as
an opportunity to revolutionize the
space I think DME is a great example of
how we can
with what we can of of what we can
replace uh LPG gas with then of course
we can also
look into other things like induction
cooking or whatever and so on. Yeah.
Omnai says if a country is a even
allowed to reproduce or they genuinely
not want to have children and your view
on yondhatu
video I have no idea who yan ihhatu is.
If a country is a vasal they most like
see in most cases vasal countries don't
even know the the people of the country
don't even know in most cases that they
are vasals
they'll reproduce and do everything
normally
nothing will change for them for the
common people until things change and
things will change in a way that don't
they don't understand
uh so Japan is a great example South
Korea is another example okay I have no
idea who Yonden I hatu is but let me see
what that is
yonden ihhatu.
What is that?
I have no idea sir. I have no idea what
that is. Nope.
Ghoulibar says you have experienced one
near supernatural unexplained thing and
you you know it. Okay. You seem to be a
longtime viewer of mine. I have
experienced one thing I can't explain
once. Only once.
Yeah, once
you got me there. You got me very good.
Yes.
Yes, indeed. Once. Once in my life.
That is probably the one experience I've
had. Yeah.
Shakpx says, "Would you watch review
Durand 2?" I do plan to watch it the
earliest review. I'll see about that,
but I'll I'll certainly watch it for
sure. And yeah, if I watch it, I will
I will share my views about it for sure
because I'm sure in the future live
streams I'll be asked about this. So if
I watch it, I certainly and I do plan to
watch it then I'll certainly share my my
views about it.
Okay. Al AI prod
Japan had prime ministers. Anyway, uh I
don't know what was was said, but I
can't watch it here live. But let's see
what did Trump say.
What did Trump say in front of the
Japanese prime minister?
Pearl Harbor joke. Really?
Seriously?
Let's see what BBC has to say.
Uh Trump compares attack on Iran to
Pearl Harbor. In meeting with Japanese
Prime Minister in a prime meeting with
Japanese Prime Minister Sai Takahi at
the old office, Trump was asked why he
didn't inform allies about his plan to
attack Iran. Trump responded by raising
Japan's attack on Pearl Harbor during
Bulvo to saying who knows better about
surprise than Japan.
Okay, so that's the kind of thing Trump
has a tendency to do. Okay,
Rahul Para says, "Are Iran units run by
Mossad targeting GCC?" No, not that I
know of.
Pratip Kumar Royce says, "How to
generate a regular stable income source
of income through trading? I've some
I've seen some people with only profits
and no loss. How is this possible?"
Well, I am the wrong person to ask this
question because I don't uh do trading.
you know trading as in stocks and shares
and what commodities, metals, minerals
etc. Yeah, I I am not into trading so I
have absolutely no idea whatsoever about
this matter. Uh there may be some people
who are absolute experts at it and who
have only profits and no loss but I
don't know how they do it. So yeah I I
don't know I don't have the answer to
your question. I'm I'm afraid. Sorry.
Godliness says in operation Sindur we
won because India was able to outperform
Pakistan in its defensive and offensive
operations. Same is with US they are
outperforming Iran in every front that
of tens of thousands of kilometers away
they win. All right sir thank you for
your for sharing your opinion and your
perspective. All right.
Mayur goer says had scanned 200
no idea of super chat
had scanned 200 no idea of super chat
what does it mean I don't know what's
your opinion on India not supporting
Afghanistan after hospital bombing of
Pakistan we should send a a cash missile
regime reg regiment I think the Indian
minister of external affairs issued a
statement a very strong statement uh
condemning the cowardly action by
Pakistan
Right. So, Vid uh offered diplomatic
strong diplomatic support Afghanistan.
Akash missile regiment and all it's too
early to do such things. Yeah.
Afghanistan
is very capable of fighting Pakistan on
its own and if they genuinely need some
support in the future, we will not
provide it or we may even provide it.
Who knows? See, Afghanistan has seen
tremendous strife in the past. The
Najiboulah government was
had excellent relations with with India
and then the Najiboula government fell
to the mujahedines
and India did nothing. So India has a
long long long
uh history and record of not interfering
in Afghanistan no matter what happens.
But we will invest in Afghanistan and
help the people of Afghanistan. So I
think it's unlikely that India will do
anything about this. But Afghan this the
the Afghanistan government Taliban
government is pretty capable of fighting
Pakistan on its own without our help and
if we send a cash missile missile
regiments if the if somebody get if
somehow some of our enemies get hold of
it they may be able to understand our
technology better so it's not a great
idea probably
Sharma photography says if every Iranian
commander is independent doesn't it make
easy to flip Well, you don't choose
commanders randomly, right?
Commanders, you think you you pick them
out of a hat?
You have commanders who are
ideologically steadfast and
ideologically
vetted.
Okay, there's a process in Iran to
ensure the right people rise to the top.
It's not like you some bring some random
guy and make him commander, right?
Please, please, that's not how the world
works.
Godliness says first the state of
hormones and Iranian oil come under
Trump's control. He can charge more
tariffs on oil. Also raise the cost of
shipping on hormones. Be the big mafia.
It's high risk high reward for the US.
Well, let Trump
take the strait of Hormos under his
control and take Iran and oil under his
control. Very easy to say, very hard to
achieve, right? So, it's not happened.
That was the objective from day one.
How much of it has happened?
Nothing has happened thus far. It may
happen tomorrow. It's always a
possibility. It may happen in 3 weeks
time, maybe in 2 days time, maybe in 4
months time, whatever. We'll see about
that.
But uh what is the amount of what's the
price Trump is willing to pay if he
wants to achieve this? Shut down the
world's LP the state of hormones and 30%
of the world's petrochemical supply. for
months.
I'm not sure if that's what he intended,
right?
And there's no indication that he is
anywhere anywhere close to achieving any
of these objectives. Okay. Arismanticor
says, "If you ask me, we should return
what our neighbors give to us with cruel
interest. Subconventional operations
should become the norm. No more moral
BS." Well, that's what Vishnu Gupta
would have said.
Vishna Gupta Chaneka would be completely
in agreement with you.
But India is the last nation to do
Chanakini properly. Right? It is our
adversaries
who are better practitioners of
Chanakini than us for some reason.
Yeah, I agree with you. I agree.
Says, how do you assess the profession
of CA chartered accountant? A very
useful profession
and uh I suppose a lucrative profession.
Yeah, you make a lot of money if you're
a charted chartered accountant.
And is it very difficult? I'm not sure.
It's just arithmetic that you're using.
I'm sure it's more than just arithmetic.
Must be pretty complex and you have to
understand a lot of laws and stuff,
legal stuff and all. So I think it's and
I think the I recently met a number of
CAS. Okay. Uh when was that?
Sometime earlier this week, I met a
number of CAS
and I learned that the CA exam is one of
the most difficult exams in the world.
Right now, it's got like a less than 10%
passing rate. Earlier, it was like one
or two% passing rate.
So, it's very hard to crack and once you
become a CA, I think you are pretty much
guaranteed
a good income and a good career. So, I
think it's great. People need that,
right?
The business world, the the the
corporate world, the government,
everybody needs CAS. So, I think it's
good. Yeah.
Yes.
Activa says, "Guys, do subscribe and
like. Make this channel India's biggest
channel. Thank you. Thanking you sir for
this." Thank you so much. Thank you so
much. Thank you so much. I really really
appreciate um your sentiment and your
message. So guys do what Activa says. Do
like and subscribe and make this channel
India's biggest channel. Thank you so
much Activa. That's so kind of you.
Thank you so much.
Marathon Gabby runner says sir you a
sovereign person in your family.
Pause.
US Russia Iran. You a sovereign person
in your fam family.
Pause. I am not sure what you're asking,
sir. I wish I understood in that in
which case I would have answered, but
I'm not exactly sure what you're asking.
Anyway, thank you for the message. Aries
Montikor says, I believe the ISRO has
found out that the current Navic has
been compromised in several launches to
support Navic are being sabotaged by
third parties. Government of India and
ISRO are recalibrating to fix this. We
will get our Navic back. I hope that we
get it back at the earliest.
Look, it's possible there have been some
elements of something being compromised.
We know that some rocket launches failed
and most likely I am very strongly
inclined to believe that these were
sabotaged. Okay?
And yet we have to plan for these
problems.
We have to plan for things being
sabotaged possibly. We have to plan for
somebody compromising some of our
assets. We have to factor these
unlikely eventualities into our planning
process,
right?
Why do we have only one production line
of PSLVs or GSLVs or whatever?
Why don't we have redundancies built
into the the process?
Why don't we have thorough vetting of
people
and proper supervision of everything?
Why don't we manufacture our own atomic
clocks
in India? Why do we rely on imported
atomic clocks?
There are so many issues
that have led to to the problem that we
are facing right now. So government and
so are recalibrating. Yes, sure. Great.
We know that. We know they will
recalibrate. They will fix it in a year
or two. But that one or two years will
be in a problem right will be
compromised and instead of recalibrating
can't you plan for these problems 10
years in advance or 5 years in advance
so that you recalibrate before it
happens
that is the problem we are reactive not
proactive
that is what frustrates me I know we
will get the Navic back eventually but
another thing that frustrates me is our
low ambition of having a regional Navik
only limited to subcontinent Why don't
we have a global navic system? Why don't
we have it? Why don't why doesn't India
have that ambition? It doesn't cost a
lot.
It costs less than one month's laroja.
I'm sure
just low ambition and low standards is
what frustrates me.
But yes, thank you for the message of
optimism and positivity. I know you're
right. We will get the Navic system back
in a year or two. But overall it's this
attitude and this approach that is
disappointing. You see
Rano Nahapana what a great name. What a
great name. Nahana
what a great man he was.
Yes the great Mahakhatraba Nahapana. No
one remembers the guy today right? One
of our great kings
in western India.
Yes. from 2,000 years ago, one of I
think his capital city. So, so Nahapana
was a Mahakhatra. Okay. A western satra.
His ancestors were skitians. He was
Indoskeian.
He was the lord and protector of
Sumnath.
And his capital city was called
Minanagar.
What is that city called today?
It's called Karachi
Nahapana. Okay. Turks providing numerous
drones to Pakistan. What to do? You
can't do something about that. But what
we can do is we can produce our own
high-quality drones and anti- drone
counter measures
to deal with any eventuality
coming from Pakistan as a consequence of
Turkish drones. That's what we can do.
hacking monks said says I'm sorry I
can't help you with that as an AI I am
pro programmed to provide answers based
on my training data which unfortunately
based on
Iran's capabilities
that's what the American AIS must have
told that military right
that is so funny
good one good one love
Uh, Pratip Kumar Royce is iron man or
Batman. Well, you know, I used to be a
big fan of Batman. As as a when I was a
kid, I watched the original Batman
series.
Okay. Uh, 1960s series. There was so
much fun. It was like a lot of humor in
there. Original Batman and Robin. Uh,
you want to see what it looks like? I'll
tell you what.
Original 1960s Batman.
Yeah. Adam West. Adam West Batman.
Right.
There we have it. This one.
This was a fun series. It was such fun
to watch. It was so humorous. It had
great villains, super villains,
characters, and all. And if you watch
today's Batman, it is so dark and
depressing. I can't stand it. So I love
the original Batman
and if you ask me today 21st century
version of Batman or Iron Man I would go
with Iron Man.
Okay. Pratep Kumar Roy says can we make
something like nuclearpowered sentinel
robots and use in wars? Maybe
a nuclearpowered robots would be very
difficult because nuclear reactors are
very very bulky. Uh
but um
but you can make uh electric powered
robots, sentient robots. No, I don't
know about sentient robots, but robots
and use them in wars. Yes, you know
various kinds of robots are available
today. Humanoid robots, dog robots,
quadruped robots, snake like robots,
mosquito robots,
bat robots. You can make robots and use
them in wars. I'm not sure about nuclear
power. I don't think we have the um I
don't think anybody has the technology
to to make nuclearpowered robots as of
today but yes robots certainly possible.
Vibhas Singh says living in Dubai
nowadays is now in news for all weak
security internally. Is this a permanent
damage or with time is it something that
will dilute with time and everybody will
be business as usual?
You know what?
Things aren't looking great.
Unfortunately, sadly, tragically, for
Dubai,
Dubai, the economic model may collapse
if this war drags on for months.
See, what is Dubai? Dubai is a gigantic
resort city. It's a resort. What's a
resort? A resort is a small habitation
thing which can cater for, let's say, 20
guests. and they have a staff of 200 to
cater for the whims and fancies and
needs of those 20 guests. Right?
So that's a resort. Dubai is a
city-sized resort and the majority of
the population is those service staff
who come from India and other countries
and who cater to the needs and
necessities and and luxuries of the
guests
which are the high income people who
come from various parts of the world
expats.
Now that economic model needs stability,
security
and peace to exist. When you have the
situation of war with Iran which is not
going away anywhere
and when Iran is in a position to target
Dubai whenever needed and the UAE
whenever needed, they that's bad for the
economic model of Dubai. If this war
ends soon, I'm hopeful that things go
back to normal, business as usual, and
people on if they feel safe, they will
return to Dubai. But right now, everyone
wants to escape Dubai,
right? People have spent hundreds of
thousands of dollars for private jet for
chartered planes to escape from Dubai. I
hope that if this war ends soon, then
things will soon be BAU.
But I am not that hopeful about that,
unfortunately. things don't look very
good. If this continues even 2 3 months
more, it will be the end of the whole
economic model. Yeah, sadly which will
be tragic for everybody. But yeah,
uh Ashish Mishra says, "I aspire to
serve India as a great leader beyond
ideology, but I'm an introvert. Please
guide me. Will you be my Chanaka
mentor?"
Um,
look um,
you aspire to serve India as a great
leader
beyond ideology. But I'm introvert.
Okay, it doesn't matter if you're
introvert or not. If you have the
leadership qualities, you'll be able to
make it happen. But you have to first
find out what your strengths and
weaknesses are. Do you have what is
called leadership qualities?
See, we all have hopes and aspirations
and so on. But our hopes, aspirations,
dreams may not always be in line with
our actual qualities. So the first thing
you have to do is to understand who you
are, what your qualities are, what your
strengths, weaknesses, all that are,
right? That's what you have to do. And
if you find that you indeed have let's
say leadership qualities, see what is
there? What is leadership about?
The core
essence of leadership is service.
Leadership is actually service. Okay?
It's not shouting at people and yelling
at people and being tall and having a
loud voice. That's not leadership.
Leadership is service.
And the more people you can serve, the
better a leader you are. Lead service at
scale is the best leadership. But of
course in you know leadership is also
about communication and setting an
example all of that. So leadership is is
set of skills that very few people
actually have. Okay. So you first decide
whether you have that or not. Determine
whether you have that or not by putting
yourself out there in positions where
you can serve where you can serve people
and serve the nation
right so you to find that out and if you
are able to actually be in a position
where you are able to lead and serve
then reach out to me and let's see if I
can be your mentor. We'll see about
that. All the best Ashish. All the best.
Argabal says if drones can drain US
missiles how defend bases subs greater
than carriers China at Tyangong space
station BYD NIO underestimated
Bur with snick future will Iran surv
what exactly is the question how many
things are you putting in this one thing
if drones drain US missiles how defend
bases you can't defend the American
bases are mostly most likely destroyed
the American bases in West Asia are most
likely destroyed.
Okay. The Bahrain base, fifth fleet base
gone. Most of it is finished. Subs
greater than carriers. Yes. Yes. Subs
always trump carriers. Okay. Carriers
are huge enticing floating targets.
Carriers are done. They're obsolete.
Yangong space station BYDO. I have no
idea. Underestimated Burvestnik future.
Burvestnik is this Russian cruise
missile. Nuclear nuclear fueled nuclear
powered cruise missile. Yeah, it could
be a game-changing weapon. Will Iran
survive? Looks like it will survive.
Okay. Arismanticor says, "Israel can do
genetic tests to determine if cookies
had Jewish ancestry. The clearly the
cookies are being willingly used as a
proxy and fortine for the US. The
cookies don't have Jewish ancestry. Let
me show you.
Cookies, genetic tests, Jewish ancestry.
What is this?
Okay.
Cookies.
Okay. Let's see. Genetic studies on the
cookie chin miso population ban bashid.
Uh mixed findings regarding Jewish
ancestry. There is no paternal links to
Middle Eastern populations. some
evidence of metitochondrial atro what
nonsense absolute nonsense
there's no traces metchondrial DNA near
eastern lineages
middle eastern Usbakistani Jewish
profiles really
okay I was not aware of that but it's
what traces traces you can find traces
of I mean you can find traces of
neanderal ancestry
in a in a human being okay.
I'm sure you'll be able to find traces
of Neanderthal ancestry in me. Little
bit of scrap of DNA somewhere. You may
be able to find traces of um what Dennis
ancestry in me. A little bit of DNA
scraps.
You may even find traces of dinosaur
ancestry in people. Who knows?
So they have done tests and they don't
they could not find any evidence of
Jewish ancestry in the cookies. Okay,
that is what it is.
Okay, Ari says unrelated a bit. Your
thoughts on love in office? Love is
love. If it happens, it happens. Whether
it's office or wherever, it's okay. I
have nothing against somebody falling in
love in office. Perfectly fine. I have
Why would I have an issue with that? Uh
that's my thoughts about it. Love is
love. If it happens, it happens. Go for
it.
Aayush says, "What are your views on
real powers that control the world? How
deep is AIPAC and other lobbies old rich
families involved in US politics?
The real powers that control the world,
it's called the deep state and we don't
know who they are but they do exist
clearly,
right? And they transcend borders and
they are based in the west somewhere
wherever maybe in multiple countries,
right? We don't quite know who they
are." Uh when it comes to the Israel and
the US relationship, the USIsrael
relationship, clearly Israel is the top
dog, the Israel has been able to drag
Israel has been able to drag the US into
this war with Iran.
They initiated the war with Iran and the
US had to then enter the war and the
Iranian Israelis are escalating the war
now and Trump is upset but he can't do
much about it beyond put posts on truth
social. Israel clearly is the dominant
partner in this tango with the US and
AIPC is this uh
pro-Jewish pro-Israel lobbying
organization or something. Uh clearly
they are uh strongly embedded in US
politics in a bipartisan fashion and
they are obviously very influential.
Clearly
Guribar says podcast with TRS was half
the area
R restricted
podcast with TRS was half the area R
restricted.
Which area was restricted? Area R.
I'm not sure what you're saying. Podcast
with TRS. Yes, I have a podcast that has
come out a day or so ago with with
Reanir on the Reanir show. and not sure
which area was restricted. Honey Sharma,
good to see you. You said even if Israel
uses the nuclear bomb, the Iranians will
fight handto- hand. But why didn't the
Japanese fight the US or at least
resist them resist them in 45?
Because Japan did not have this
decentralized leadership. Japan, good
question. Japan had a single point of
failure,
the top leadership.
Okay.
And when the top leadership surrendered,
the whole population of Japan
surrendered. Japan had the societal
structure was that it was deeply
obedient to the emperor.
What the emperor said was the word of
God. If the emperor said do this, you
would do it.
Right? So the emperor's word was the
word of God. If the emperor gives an
order, the entire population of Japan
would obey.
So after the Americans tested two
nuclear devices on the people of Japan,
the emperor said, "We surrender." And
the entire population of Japan obeyed.
Now see Iran. Totally different. There
is no emperor. The supreme leader if he
dies, he's a martyr. He's a shahid. And
that makes Iran the Muslim nation and
the Americans the zalim.
And Iranian culture is Shia Islam
culture. It's the culture of martyrdom
shahadat. And they have declared jihad
which means every Muslim fights
and they have this concept of mosaic
warfare, decentralized warfare. Even if
all the leaders are killed, the people
will will keep fighting and they will
seek martyrdom. That's a difference
cultural difference between the two
nations. See that's why but excellent
question that uh that force me to drill
drill deeper into these concepts.
Excellent question.
Pratar Dhana says Russi medical aid to
Iran. What medical aid? Are they
offering medical aid to Iran? I'm not
sure. Medical aid really
Russian medical aid to Iran.
esteemed kind people. Russia sends
massive aid to Iran. Really?
Russia becomes first country to say send
aid to Iran. Sends 13 turns of emergency
medical supplies.
Interesting.
So medical aid seems to be in uh
quotation marks. Well, we know. We don't
know. Okay. Interesting. Interesting
though. Yeah. Could be something else
perhaps. Who knows? Fabin Thomas says
most of what he said has played out.
Given these things our government knows
too. Why don't we act on it to get
leverage? Why did we give in into the
US? I I don't know maybe look I don't
face the constraints that the government
of India is under
right. I don't know the secret things
about the world that the government of
India may be privy to and maybe the
government of India does things
differently because they are aware of
things that I'm not aware of. I discuss
things that I see in the public domain.
I don't have access to classified
information.
I don't have access to
intelligence that you know is is is
secret
and sensitive.
So maybe there are things that I'm not
aware of.
uh clearly like much of what I have said
is kind of you know turned out to be
true and kind of played out the way I've
said
and obviously the government of India
will know the things probably much
better than what I know.
Um the only thing I I can imagine is
that there are constraints India faces
that I'm not aware of
and maybe the Americans have various
forms of leverage over India that I'm
not aware of. Maybe India is compromised
at at certain levels that I'm not not
aware of. I don't know. I don't know. So
clearly there are things that I am not
aware of. Some things I'm aware of that
India is penetrated by the Americans at
various levels.
One very open example is so many
government officials have families and
children who live in the US and who are
American citizens. There is clear that
is clear blatant compromise. So if your
children are American citizens, where
will your allegiance lie? Will it lie
with India or with the US? And we have
so many officials like that at various
levels in the government. That is a
clear example of India being compromised
and penetrated. Then there must be so
many other things that I'm not aware of.
So you see
yeah
says F-35 has been hit by a SAM. It's a
big deal. A surfaceto-air missile. Let's
let's check again.
F-35. Is there some more news that's
come out?
Okay. So it's been hit by a
surfaceto-air missile most likely.
Right.
Uh what do we have here? There's a video
of it which I'll not play here.
Um so Iran has taken out uh an American
F-35. The crown jewel of the American
Air Force, the F-35,
the most expensive
flying trash can in the world.
Hm. And the Iranians have taken out one
of these with a surfaceto-air missile.
It's not a big deal. It's a huge deal.
Yeah. And they they want India to buy
F-35s.
Would you believe it?
Okay. Golibar says, "Mind sharing the
unexplained thing?" That's a long story.
It's It's too long to be shared here.
Maybe in the future I'll do it. It's a
long story. It it'll take proper setup
and explanation of parameters and
dimensions and whatn not to actually for
you to understand what that unexplained
thing was. It'll take a long time to
explain
to for you to be able to understand why
it was unexplainable. Right? So not not
today but I will one of these days.
Omnak says Yonden Lu video from South
China Morning Post.
Okay, let's see. Yanden Lu video from
South China Morning Post.
Yon
Yonden Lu
video Yanden Lu
condemns America and you Israel. Okay.
Who is this person? Chief editor
Yonden Lu
condemns America etc.
Okay. There are lots of videos of this
person. I'm not sure which video you
would like me to see but
yeah.
Okay. Anyway, thank you for the
recommendation. Thank you. Godliness
says, "Happy Hindu New Year to you and
all your viewers. May this new year
bring prosperity, health and wealth for
the followers of the Samatan Vic
Dharma." Thank you very much and I thank
you for your very kind wishes to me and
to everyone else and I wish the same to
you godliness and to all our viewers.
Thank you.
Bhav Singh says guide me on gold and
silver prices. I am not the guy to guide
you on this. I am not an expert in gold
and silver prices and all that stuff.
I'm not the guy for this. I'm very
sorry.
Marathon Gabby runner says, "Sir, you
are a sovereign person in your family."
Do families have sovereign people and
vasals?
What does that mean?
Do we have vasals in families?
Do we do you need to be fully sovereign,
half sovereign? I'm not sure what the
question is, but I suppose we are all
sovereign individuals, aren't we? Or are
we not? I have not tried ever thought of
applying sovereignty and wasalhood to
families. So no don't know noob just
life. Thank you very much. Noob just
life. Thank you sir.
Okay
co kodand rapper kodand rala says big
fan of you. Thank you very much sir.
Thank you very much. I saw the news that
Ukrainians six Ukrainians and one
American got arrested in the east of
India and that has something to do with
drones. Is our government finally taking
some action? Thanks for your wisdom.
First of all, thank you very much. Uh
yes, we've had one American uh
troublemaker with a long history of
troublemaking in various conflict zones.
Matthew Fandike,
that one American person has been
arrested and six Ukrainian mercenaries
were arrested in the eastern part of
India, far eastern part of India,
Gujhati and so on so forth.
and they were arrested because they were
um
what they were doing was they were they
were uh providing terrorism training and
drone training to cookie terrorists in
Burma. So they were crossing over into
Burma from India's far east, India's
border with Burma. Crossing over into
Burma and providing ter training,
military training to to cookie
terrorists and they were providing
drones to these terrorists,
right? And these drones were being
smuggled through India into Myanmar
and this was going on for God knows how
long. So that's why these individuals
have been arrested and this arrest was
made very public. So it looks like the
government of India is send at least the
least that's happening is that India is
sending a message to the United States
and to Ukraine. Ukraine doesn't matter.
Ukraine is a vasal of the US. This is a
message to the government of the US. And
right after this happened the American
uh ambassador Sergio Gore met with
India's national security adviser Mr.
Ajit Dwal. So clearly our government is
taking some action. Now what is the
extent of the action going to be is the
question. Right now this has happened
but does this mean that India is going
going to finally crack down on cookie
terrorism in Manipur? I don't know about
that. I hope so but it's too early to
say right that's what's the deal.
Sumit says top countries to pursue a PhD
in international relations. No idea.
Probably the US maybe Singapore.
Um
yeah I don't know. Singapore probably US
definitely other countries I don't know
noob just life says what you think about
aliens from Nagaloka have visited the
earth I don't know I have
since childhood been fascinated with
aliens extraterrestrial life UFOs all
that stuff because of my inclinations
towards science right
I've always wondered what was going on
out air.
As a kid, I used to spend hours at night
staring out at the Milky Way and the
stars and galaxies
at a time when there was very little
life light pollution. So, you could
actually see stars and if you spent one
hour looking at the sky, you would see
several satellites pass by. You could
see satellites passing by, you know, and
you would see meteors. So I spend a lot
of time thinking about these you know
these ponderous matters and I'll be the
happiest person to find evidence if I
were to find evidence any evidence of
aliens having visited the earth but thus
far I have found not one piece of hard
undeniable evidence that alien
that aliens have visited our planet. Oh,
I haven't I haven't found that evidence
ever. Nimish Gupta says 23 male December
24 mechanical graduate interest killed
by outdated syllabus explored fit
applied to 100 plus jobs built AI
company research tool so limits ability
worry now
okay so you're 23 you're a male you
graduated in 24 December mechanical
engineering your interest was scaled by
outdated syllabus that yeah I understand
explored faith applied to more than 100
jobs. built AI company research tool.
Okay, that's good. So, you are someone
who's capable of building stuff. Soul
limits, hirability, worry. Now, you know
what? Create a public portfolio
of what you are capable of building and
what you have built in the past. Make it
on public. Put it all on GitHub.
Whatever, right? All the tools, all the
whatever you create, put it up on all of
that on GitHub. Keep keep tinkering,
keep producing, keep keep creating
things and keep applying to jobs. As
long as you are someone who can create
stuff and and produce either new tools
or new solutions, you should not have a
problem getting hired. I mean if I was
running an software firm, IT firm,
whatever, and if you are somebody who
actually took the initiative to to try
something like this, you built an AI
company, you did a research tool or
whatever, I would be very happy to hire
you. Yeah.
So don't be discouraged.
Just keep building in public and keep
applying. I'm sure it'll work out for
you, right? Be positive, be optimistic,
and keep working hard and keep working
smart. All the best. Nimish
Fabin Thomas says, "How long will China
and Russia wait to make their military
moves? I'm assuming they'll be fools not
to do right now as when has US been this
vulnerable?"
I think it makes sense to wait a little
longer.
See, right now, the longer the US fights
this war, the more they're going to be
depleted of of critical
things like arms, ammunition,
interceptor missiles, TAD systems, um,
uh, radars,
uh, tomahawk missiles, all of that. And
they don't have the military industrial
complex, the kind of military industrial
complex that produces tens of thousands
of drones a year and thousands of
missiles a year. It produces a handful,
maybe a 100 tomahawk missiles per year.
And to ramp up production, to scale up
production will take months or years.
So I think it makes sense for the
Chinese and Russians to wait a few more
months until the American stockpiles are
significantly depleted, even more than
the depletion that they face right now
and then make your move. Yeah, I think
well
see if China makes a move on Taiwan the
Americans will press South Korea and
Japan into action against their wishes.
Doesn't matter what they wish.
So the question is is China willing to
take some damage in order to acquire
Taiwan because see South Korea and
Russia and Japan will definitely get
involved in a war with China if China
makes a move on Taiwan and it means
China will take some damage. China's
economic base, its industrial base will
take some damage,
right? To win a war, you would take some
damage. Is China willing to take the
damage? Is China
Does China have some appetite for risk
and some damage? In case it does have
some appetite for risk and damage,
I think the best time to make a move in
the is in the next few months. And same
for Russia. Same for Russia.
Rahu says, "Which software do you use
for streaming? Are you streamyard?
Honey Sharma says, "What will you watch
past Durand 2 or Tumb? I think it's
going to be Durand 2 most likely." Tumb.
Yeah, thank you for the reminder.
Yeah, I still need to watch that as
well. I think most likely it's going to
be Durand 2 first. Okay, but thank you
for the reminder. Goullibar says,
"Travel areas suggested in TRS most are
restricted."
Okay, what were the travel areas we
discussed? I don't quite recall right
now.
I'm sure there was Egypt.
I don't remember the others. It's been a
while since we recorded the podcast
actually, so I don't remember the travel
areas, but it is what it is.
Um, Krishnan Balo has come back from the
movie. It was bloody amazing. My live
stream has been so long that an entire
movie was done in the meanwhile. I'm
glad you liked it. I plan to watch it
too. Vishal Ro says, "Netanyahu is live
currently." So, he's alive. Well, good
for Nathaniel. Good for him. Good for
him.
Gulibar says, "Please perhaps share the
story in TRS his genre."
Good suggestion indeed. Lakshi Kana
says, "How can I build the habit of
reading diverse books to improve my
understanding, writing, vocabulary and
grammar?" You how do you build the habit
of running?
You start by running. Maybe you start by
running five minutes a day, but you
start. How do you build the habit of
going to gym and working out and
building big muscles? You start by going
for 10 minutes a day, right? So, how do
you build the habit of reading diverse
books? First, you buy a number of books,
five, six books. Then you spend like 10
minutes a day reading. Just start with
10. Let's say you tell yourself, I'm
going to read just three pages a day.
You do that for a week. Then increase to
five pages a day next week. Then
increase to 10 pages a day next week.
and maybe 20 pages a day by by the end
of the first month. That's how you build
a habit, right? Good habit to have. Do
it. The naked drummer says need reforms,
accountability and compensation
based on performance. I agree with you.
Yeah, we need uh reforms in the Indian
bureaucracy.
Accountability very important.
Compensation based on performance.
Lateral hiring, hiring and firing, all
of these things are needed. It needs to
be turned into a professional force,
right? I agree with you. Absolutely.
Vishilage says, "Hypothetically, can
India take over GCC using the Indians
living there by creating revolutions?"
Um
well hypothetically
possible to some extent but uh
practically very difficult
very difficult practically
because who owns the means of violence?
the local governments, right? The means
of violence means uh the police force,
the armed force, all of that, right?
That's all all in the hands of the local
governments
and maybe 60% of the people there are of
subcontinental origin, but they are not
armed. Without arms, what can you do?
And first of all, we don't even want
this to happen, right? I'm not
suggesting they should happen, but as a
as an academic exercise, it's almost
impossible for this to succeed.
Pratush Sharma says US training its
military AI for future wars. It's using
AI in the current war. It's using the
current AI in the current war for
selecting targets and god knows what
else. It's already happening in real
time. It is. So yeah, and also for
future wars. Yes. Arian Shukla says, "My
girlfriend from Iran told me that they
have their own apps for communication.
Don't India develop apps for their own
people and rely on US apps for such
tasks. We can certainly develop our own
apps. You see Russia has its own apps.
China has its own apps. Iran has its own
apps. But India Vishwaguru has no apps.
This I mean of course India can develop
its own apps. The government needs to
show some spine and some willingness to
do some difficult things but the
government seems to be on wanting the
easy way out of everything. Right?
We are integrating Google more and more
into our ecosystem. the government of
India is doing the exact opposite of
what should be done. Uh what the reason
is I don't know but it is what it is
right. So yeah
so yeah it's interesting know that even
Iran has this right.
Yeah yeah India should also learn from
nations like Iran but we I don't think
we will or I don't think the government
wants to for whatever reason. Okay.
Okay. Anyhow all right that brings me to
the end.
of today's live stream.
Yeah,
that brings me to the end of today's
live stream. Thank you so much everybody
for the questions
and uh I will see you in the next live
stream which will happen very soon in a
couple of days. Until then, take care
everybody. Keep learning, keep asking
questions, keep raising your standards
and I look forward to seeing you very
soon. Hopefully with better news in the
war. Maybe the war ends hopefully. But
we'll see about that. Thank you so much
everyone. I'll see you very soon. Take
care. Bye-bye. Good night. Good day.